[Music]
Greetings. Greetings everyone. Go ahead,
Tante. Go ahead.
>> No, go ahead. I'm so used to saying
welcome. But you did it. You said
greetings. That's great.
>> Yeah. Uh, well,
>> they probably saw my lips for me,
>> but that's okay.
>> So, please go ahead and put a one in the
chat if you could hear us. Um, we are uh
excited to be on tonight.
>> Yes.
>> Uh, a lot of important things to share.
So, we're just going to wait to See if
we get some ones in the chat.
>> Yeah, put a one in the chat if you can
hear us. Just want to say welcome. Happy
Sabbath to you all where the where it's
Sabbath. I saw somebody put in the chat
they're in, I think, Compton,
California. They're still It's not
Sabbath yet. The sun is still up. And
so, um, but welcome and happy Sabbath to
those. Great. Got the ones.
>> Got the ones.
>> Happy Sabbath to those where the Sabbath
has it where it's Sabbath.
>> Yes.
So, we are happy to be here with you
this evening. Um, so many times if you
watch our church service, you know, I
wear uh shirts with a message on it. And
tonight, I don't I have a message and
the message is just inviting you to
church tomorrow.
>> So, this is not this is not our church.
This is Power of the Lamb Ministries,
which is uh our personal ministry. And
but I do want to take this time to
invite you to church because I never
wear this on the service, but I was
like, I have this shirt. Let me wear it
tonight. Uh so yeah, Living Manage
Church is the church that he pastors and
um he is the senior pastor there and
it's all online. So some of you, some of
our members are here, some of you don't
have never worshiped with us before, but
please join us tomorrow on YouTube. You
can use the same YouTube channel, but we
have we also have uh my Living Mana,
which is the official YouTube channel
for Living Mana Church, and it starts at
12 PM Central time. So if you don't plan
to be anywhere else, you can join us.
Join us, please. We would love to have
you uh worship with us tomorrow.
You guys need to share this link. I'm
going to tell you right now that um for
those that may I don't know how many of
you have saw saw our back to basic
series. This was like, you know, it's
almost four and a half almost five years
ago. It's been that long. Um, but if you
remember
my amazement and astonishment and shock
as we were going through that study,
especially at a certain part of that
study, tonight is going to be no
different than that. So, I can say that
you're going to want to share this link
on your social media and invite people
to come in and just to to worship with
us, to learn, to study together. That's
what we're doing. We're studying
together.
>> Amen. Amen. And Jesus, I see you.
>> Yes. Hey Jesus, good to see you in my
>> in my hometown where I grew up from six
years old. Pastor Robels, California.
>> Yeah,
>> good to see you here.
>> So, you guys, we are just we're just
about to jump in. Um
>> Yeah,
>> because there's a lot to cover and my
wife and I already had the talk about
how long this is going to last.
>> Yep, we had the talk and you guys know
my role. It's not just timekeeper, time
helper, I guess I should say. And um to
if you those of you because some people
are saying they did watch back to the
basics and remember um I was trying to
help him keep it at a level which I
don't think will be that hard this time
maybe hopefully of a 10-year-old could
understand it. So that's still my role.
>> Yeah.
>> While I'm learning with you as well.
>> Yeah. So we are going to be covering a
lot tonight. And you may you you you
might hear some things that you have
never heard before
>> which um
yeah just buckle your seat belts. Um,
so guys, uh, I have a few videos that
I'm going to be playing and I'm hoping
that they are going to work. And in
fact,
I'm going to do something real quick.
I'm just going to play a portion of one
video and I just want to make sure that
you guys could hear it. So
>> So it's a test.
>> Yes, this is a test. if you don't mind.
Um, I am going to,
let's see here.
Yeah, I'm going to go ahead and play one
video.
>> The whole thing or
>> not the whole thing? Not the whole
thing. Just one
>> uh one segment. Here we go. And I just
need to make sure that you guys could
hear
>> that the right will stay united for as
long as it takes. Uh and because we've
identified that enemy, we've identified
that enemy is the left
>> and that the left wants to destroy
everything that's good, true, and
beautiful.
>> All right.
>> I think they're saying our volume is
low. So I think um
we have to be as as possible.
>> Did you guys hear that?
>> Okay.
>> Yes,
>> we got one. Yes. So, very good. That's
>> all I needed to know. Excellent.
Excellent. Excellent.
Okay. So,
um we're going to have a word of prayer
and then we are going to All right. Is
our audio good? Let me just
>> I know we're getting this mic up here as
possible.
>> Audio good.
>> Y'all are saying it's louder than us.
Louder than me.
>> All right. Well, we'll just use our full
outside voices inside.
>> Okay.
So, let's pray and then I'm going to
kind of open up I'll open up the study
kind of setting the foundation um and
why we're doing this study. Um and then
we're going to get into our PowerPoint.
All right.
>> Okay.
>> So, Atante, would you pray for us,
please?
>> Heavenly Father, Lord, just want to
thank you for the Sabbath. Um I know for
some Sabbath is not yet, but I just ask
that you would just bless um all of us
on this Sabbath day. Lord, just take us
give us your Holy Spirit. Take us deeper
into your word as we do this Bible study
together. And we ask all these things in
Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. All right, guys. So, um
the if you have seen my
um
back to basics series or the elephant in
the room series or the Matthew 24
series, if you haven't seen those, I
would I would strongly encourage you to
go back and watch those.
>> They are years old, but they are
absolutely significant.
>> They're not that old. Like I mean back
to basics.
>> Oh yeah. Back to basics is the oldest.
Back to Bas is almost five. The rest of
them came after that.
>> Came after. Right. So they're all within
the last five years.
>> Yeah.
>> Absolutely significant right now like
down to this day.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. So if you haven't seen that, I'm
going to encourage you to go back and
watch those those three series.
>> So guys, we are in a place right now in
our church where there's a lot going on.
There's a lot going on outside the
church. There's a lot going on inside
the church.
>> Yes.
>> Um, tomorrow morning I'm going to be
preaching a message called
Left Jesus, Right Jesus.
You're not going to want to miss that
message.
>> No.
>> Um,
there's a lot happening in our church.
And what I want to present tonight
is
the idea that much of what is happening
in our church
revolves around our understanding of one
very specific verse. And that verse is
Revelation 13 verse 11
>> where John says, "I saw another beast
coming up out of the earth. He had horns
like a lamb and spake like a dragon.
And the issue before us which has become
a pretty significant
question in our church today
>> is did this beast has this beast yet
spoken like a dragon? We're going to
find out who the beast is if you don't
know. We're going to talk about talk
about all that tonight. But has this
beast
spoken as a dragon in the past
>> or has the beast not yet spoken like a
dragon and will speak like a dragon in
the future? That's the question.
>> And people in the church are divided on
that question. And I'll tell you from my
discussions with many many many many
many many people it is almost down the
line
of if you believe that the beast has
spoken like a dragon in the past.
You have one view of everything that's
going on today. Mhm.
>> If you believe that the beast has not
yet spoken like a dragon, you have
another view of what's going on in our
society today.
>> It's almost as if that one verse
reveals a whole lot about where we are,
who we are, what we believe. And man,
it's really, really, really, really,
really, really significant. Yeah. So,
>> I don't want to take you off course.
Okay.
>> Okay. Well, I Let me not take you off
course. Go ahead. When it when it's
time, I'll say it.
>> Okay.
>> I remember it.
>> So, so those who who believe that the
beast has not yet spoken like a dragon
>> have one view of America. Those who
believe that the beast has spoken like a
dragon in the past has another view of
America.
And both of the these two views pretty
much again summarize can pretty much
summarize where you stand on almost
every other issue
>> that's going on in the church today.
>> Now, I'm not saying that's that's the
case 100%.
>> But what what I am saying is that by far
this is the majority, right? This is it
is this is 99% of the time. And I'm
throwing that number out there. I know I
haven't taken any polls, but I'm saying
that what I found in my personal
experience,
>> you believe this about Revelation 13:11,
I can tell you where you stand on
everything else. You believe this about
Revelation 13:11, I can tell you where
you stand on everything else. So, with
that in mind, we are going to jump into
this study.
>> Yes.
>> Tonight,
>> and the question that is on the table
is, how should we understand Revelation
chapter 13 verse 11? By the way, those
who believe that that that that
Revelation 13 uh 11 is yet future have
this thing of, you know, we can't
disrespect our country and it there
there's a greater sense I think of
protecting the country,
>> right? Versus those who believe that
>> it has been happening since the past.
It's not a sense of don't protect the
country, but it's more of a sense of
hey, we got to stay focused on what
prophecy says about this particular
beast.
>> So, two separate views
leading to two different outcomes.
>> Let's talk. I'm going to share my
screen. Um, and we're doing things a
little bit different tonight. Usually,
uh, you know, we have our people in the
background helping us, but we are going
to be we're actually going live straight
through reream. So, the way I'm sharing
my slides tonight might be a little bit
of an issue, but let's let's go. So,
>> share my screen
and
all right. So, I'm just gonna This may
be a little bit challenging, but can you
guys see this? Are you guys good with
the screen? Is this a good size for
everybody?
This is probably the only way that we
can, you know, switch back and forth
between slides. So, we're just going to
go with this. Um, and we're going to
read this first verse. So, Revelation
13:11, uh, the Bible says, "And I beheld
another beast coming up out of the
earth, and he had two horns like a lamb,
and he spake as a dragon, and he
exercisth all the power of the first
beast before him, and cause the earth,
and them that dwell therein to worship
the first beast, whose deadly wound was
healed?" So again, the question is, who
is this beast? Okay, some of you guys
are saying it is. Okay.
>> Some say yes, some say
>> some say yes. A little small. If you
have glasses,
>> I think that's one of our church members
that are used to
>> Yeah.
>> the other way. Um, but they're they're
pretty people are saying they're good.
Some are saying it's small just fine.
>> All right. I'm going to be reading this
anyway. And obviously you guys know I'm
going to make my slides available.
>> So listen and take notes. Yeah.
>> So you can also go back and check the
scriptures. So once again um just you
know cheat sheet version we believe that
this beast in Revelation chapter 13:11
represents represents the United States
of America
but
we're going to study this out. We're
going to study this out. Okay. Um Okay.
So, first thing we want to do is what I
want you to understand that is that
there's a lot of people that
misunderstand
or don't understand completely what this
text is talking about.
>> Okay?
>> Um, so let me show you something. We're
going to
we're not going to start with the beast
from the earth. We're actually going to
start with the beast from the sea.
And let's pretend that we have no idea
about what this is talking about, who
it's talking about. I'm going to simply
ask you the question, is this beast,
does this power seem like a good power
or a bad power? Okay, so let's read Gen
uh Revelation 13:1.
And I stood upon the sand of the sea,
and saw a beast rise up uh out of the
sea, having seven heads. Let's do this.
Let me try this. Um having seven heads,
and 10 horns,
>> and upon his horns 10 crowns, and upon
his heads the name of blasphemy.
>> And the beast which I saw was like unto
a leopard, and his feet were as a feet
of a bear, and his mouth is the mouth of
a lion. And the dragon gave him his
power, and his seed in great authority.
And I saw one of his heads as it were
wounded to death, and his deadly wound
was healed. And all the world wondered
after the beast. All the world wondered
after the beast. Okay. So, um, if I were
to ask you the question, hey guys, do
you think this is a bad from the
description, bad beast or good beast?
How would you answer?
I'll read on. Uh, Revelation 13:4. Go
ahead and put your answer in the chat.
Revelation 13:4. And they worshiped the
dragon who gave power unto the beast.
And they worshiped the beast, saying,
Who is like unto the beast? Who is able
to make war with him? And there was
given him a mouth speaking great things
and blasphemies. And power was given
unto him to continue 40 and two months.
And he opened his mouth in blasphemy
against God to blasphe his name and his
tabernacle and them that dwell in
heaven. So I think the answer is obvious
here. Without knowing who this beast is,
we would say bad beast.
>> Yes,
>> bad beast. Okay. Now, I'm going to go to
Revelation
11 because there's another beast
uh described as the beast from the
bottomless pit. And let's read about
this beast in Revelation 11:3.
The Bible says, "I will give power unto
my two witnesses." That would be the Old
Testament and the New Testament. They
shall prophesy a,23 score days clothed
in sackcloth. These are the two olive
trees and the two candlesticks standing
before the God of the earth. And if any
man will hurt them, fire proceedth
proceedth out of his mouth and devour
devour their enemies. And if any man
will hurt them, he must in this manner
be killed. Reading on, these have power
to shut heaven that it rain not in the
days of their prophecy, and have power
over waters to turn them to blood, and
to smite the earth with all plagues as
often as they will. And when they shall
have finished their testimony, the beast
that ascendeth out of the bottomless pit
shall make war against them, and shall
overcome them and kill them. All right.
So, bad beasts or good beasts? Yeah. You
have no idea who this beast is or what
this represents. What do you think? This
beast that comes out of the bottom of
this pit, bad beast or good beast?
Go ahead and put your answer in the
chat.
>> You don't know who it is. You're just
asking a question just from reading. Bad
beast, good beast. And I'm pretty sure
that every one of you are going to put
bad beast.
>> Bad beast.
>> Just by the description,
>> bad beast. Okay. So, let's go ahead and
now we're going to go to Revelation
chapter 13 verse 11. Now remember, we
don't know anything about Bible
prophecy. We don't know uh what's being
discussed here. All we know is that this
next beast is coming up out of the
earth. And we're going to read about his
description. Mhm.
>> So it says, "And I beheld another beast
coming up out of the earth, and he had
two horns like a lamb, and he spake as a
dragon, and he exercised all the power
of the first beast before him, and cause
the earth, and them that dwell therein
to worship the first beast, whose deadly
wound was healed.
And he doeth great wonders, that he
maketh fire come down from heaven on the
earth in the sight of men, and deceiveth
them that dwell on the earth by the
means of those miracles, which he had
power to do in the sight of the beast,
saying to them that dwell on the earth,
that they should make an image to the
beast, which had the wound by a sword,
and did live. And he had power to give
life unto the image of the beast, that
the image of the beast should both
speak, and cause that as many as would
not worship the image of the beast
should be killed. Let's stop right
there.
And again, we're going to ask the simple
question. Um, bad beast or good beast.
Again, you have no idea what this
represents. So, putting aside
whatever knowledge you may have just
from the description of this power,
>> bad beast or good beast.
Go ahead, put it in the chat. Bad, good,
and then put confused if you're
confused.
So, you have three options. You can
either put bad, bad beast, good beast
>> or confused
>> or confused.
Or you could even put good then bad
if you want to put that.
All right. So I'm seeing bad, bad, bad.
No one's saying good. Now we got 374
people on here and I know that there are
differing opinions on this. So
either the beast is bad or the beast is
good. It can't be both, right? There's
no good and bad. A a good good tree
doesn't bring forth bad fruit and a bad
tree doesn't bring forth good fruit.
>> No.
>> So the beast is either good or bad.
>> All right. Let me ask it this way. Um
should we in any way be defending the
first beast, the beast from the sea?
If we're defending the beast from the
sea,
what are we doing?
>> You're defending a bad beast.
>> You're defending a bad beast, right?
You're protecting a bad beast against
what God says about the beast. He's
saying, "No, no, no, no. What God said
about the beast isn't, you know, isn't."
So,
>> okay, we have one good then bad.
>> Okay, so we got a good then bad. Um, and
maybe there are there are there other
good than bads coming in,
>> but right now I'm seeing mostly bad.
>> Um,
is there at any point that we should be
defending the beast from that abyss,
that bottomless pit, whoever that beast
is, you don't know who the beast is.
Should we be defending that beast?
>> No. No. What about this beast from the
from the earth? Should we be defending
this beast?
Now, this is where you're going to see a
whole bunch of people wanting to type
yes.
>> We have one confused and one good and
bad.
>> One confused, one good and bad. So,
someone tell me, should we be defending
this beast?
Now, there's a lot of people that are
actually defending
this beast in prophecy.
There's there's there's, you know, one
group that says the beast is bad and has
been bad from the beginning. There's
another group that says, "No, the beast
is not bad. It's not bad now,
>> but it will be bad in the in the
>> towards the end."
So now you see the dilemma
and and probably the reason why most
people are confused is because the beast
has
horns like a lamb. Everybody put a one
in the chat if you're like, "Okay, I can
see how people would be confused."
Put a one in the chat if you're like,
"Okay, yeah, that makes sense. That
makes sense." Like
>> the lamb represents Jesus. The lamb
represents Jesus, right?
>> There are some nice things
attributes
about a bad beast.
>> That's that's what that's what the
>> that's what someone would say.
>> Yeah.
There there's good things about this
beast.
>> There's good things about this beast.
>> We we won't say it about the first
beast. We won't say it about the second
beast,
>> but because of the because of the
lamblike,
>> but because the text says horns like a
lamb,
>> there's a little bit of confusion.
>> There's like, oh, maybe it starts good
>> and then later it speaks like a dragon.
>> And that's what a lot of us believe,
right? That it starts good and then
speaks like a dragon later.
>> Go ahead. Your thoughts, your question,
well, your comment.
That's as humans reading into putting
we're putting things into the text that
are not there.
>> We're reading something into the text
that and I'm going to get to that. Mhm.
>> But I'm telling you again, this is the
reason why there is so much division
over this text,
>> which like I said,
>> when you believe it one way, you are apt
to follow a certain phil uh philosophy,
a certain approach,
>> or if you as if you believe it the other
way, you're apt to say, "Yeah, yeah,
yeah, no, no, this is not the right
way." So, we got to figure out what is
the text actually saying, right?
>> Okay. So,
so far uh we've we've seen bad beast
from the sea, bad beast from the earth,
>> uh from the abyss, and bad beast from
the earth. Now, here's the dilemma.
Okay?
America is the land of the free. Mhm.
>> And there's a lot of good qualities
about America. There are. You ask
anybody in the world right now, hey,
where you know, would you rather live
here or would you rather live someplace
else? And you know what? America affords
freedoms
>> that we don't have any place else. And
so there's a confusion, a disconnect in
the mind because it's like, well, how
can I say America is bad? The text says
that this beast is bad. So you telling
me that America is bad? How how can that
be? If we believe this beast is America,
right?
>> And if you believe that about this
beast, then you are disrespecting
America.
>> You are speaking against America.
>> All right. Every everybody understand
the dilemma.
>> It's an understandable dilemma.
>> Yeah. Because in America, we have the
Constitution, we have the Declaration of
Independence, we got all these things
that that really make America a unique
place.
>> Now,
let's unlock the first mystery. All
right, y'all ready for mindb blown thing
number one? Here we go.
>> Yes.
>> Mind-blown thing number one.
Here is a problem, you guys.
Let's go to Revelation 11:7. We're going
to go back to Revelation 11:7.
And uh you can see here the text says,
"And when they shall have finished their
testimony, the beast that ascendeth out
of the bottomless pit shall make war
against them, and shall overcome them
and kill them." Now,
we know what this beast represents.
Yeah. Um I'm going to read to you from
uh the pen of inspiration. I'm going to
show you. Watch this.
According to the words of the prophet,
then a little before the year 1798,
um, some power of satanic origin and
character would rise to make war upon
the Bible. And in the land where the
testimony of God's two witnesses should
thus be silenced, there would be
manifest the atheism of the Pharaoh and
the lentiousness of Sodom. This prophecy
received a most exact and striking
fulfillment in the history of France.
again. Hold on. So, what nation is being
pointed out here?
Let me pull this back up. What nation is
being is represented here?
We just read it. What is the what is the
nation being represented in these
verses? What does the pen of inspiration
say? What do we believe as a church?
This nation
is
who?
Wow, there's a super delay.
>> Yeah, we have a delay.
>> There's a super delay. Um,
it's France.
>> Very good. It's France. All right,
everybody put a one in the chat if you
get it. You knew that. Yeah, France. I
knew that. Now, here's a question, guys.
Is the beast out of the abyss France?
Yes or no? Is the beast out of the abyss
France? Now, you might be like, "Hold
on, pastor. You just said that the
nation being spoken of here is France.
Why are you asking us if the beast out
of the abyss is France?"
You just answered the question. Let me
ask it again. And I know there's a day
delay, so let me ask it again. Is the
beast from the abyss France? Does it
represent
France?
Yes. One in the chat for yes.
One in the chat for yes. No. Two in the
chat for yes. I'm sorry cuz y'all are
putting ones and I don't know if I'd
asked for one before, but put a two in
the chat for yes. And I'm going to tell
you this right now. The answer is no.
The beast from the abyss is not France.
Let's go back to the screen.
And I want you to notice again what the
pen of inspiration says.
This is atheism.
And the nation represented by Egypt
would give voice to a similar denial of
the claims of the living God and would
manifest a like spirit of unbelief and
defiance. The great city is also
compared spiritually to Sodom. The
Sodom, the corruption of Sodom and
breaking the law of God was especially
manifested in lensiousness.
And this sin was also to be a preeminent
characteristic of the nation that would
fulfill the specifications of the
scripture.
Listen to me guys.
France is the where
but not the who.
>> Okay.
France is simply giving you giving you
the location of the power
that is being described and the power
that is being described is atheism.
>> Right. But in France that's where it
flourished.
>> That's right. So in other words,
the prophecy
is pointing out the power of atheism and
it's simply referring to France as the
place in which that power would rise.
>> Everybody put a five in the chat if you
get that. France is the where, but it is
not the who. The who is atheism. Okay.
>> Okay. Are we good?
Let's now go to the beast in Revelation
chapter 13 verse1. And y'all might be
getting ready to catch on to this.
Revelation 13:1.
And I stood upon the sand of the sea and
saw a beast rise about the sea having
seven heads and 10 horns. And upon his
horns 10 crowns, and upon his heads the
name of blasphemy. And we know we're
going to read this beast was like a lion
and a a a leopard and a bear. And his
mouth is a mouth of a lion. So here's a
question. Who is what is this beast?
Where does this beast rise?
Where is this beast? What is this verse
pointing to? What place?
What place?
The place
is what everybody? It's Rome.
>> The place is Rome.
But is Rome the beast from the sea?
Yes or no? Everybody, is Rome the beast
from the sea?
No. No. No. No. No. Rome is not the
beast from the sea. Rome is simply the
place
>> that's going to help us to identify the
power
>> and the power is the papacy.
>> Everybody put a chat a one in the chat
>> if you get that. The beast power doesn't
have borders.
>> The beast power doesn't have borders,
>> Rome is the place,
>> but the beast itself, the power itself
is the papacy. And now, now y'all are
getting ready to under now you
understand. I I don't think I even need
to say anything. Y'all put a seven in
the chat if you're like, "Pastor, we are
already with you." Put a seven in the
chat if you're saying to yourself,
"Pastor, we already
got it."
We already
got it.
In Revelation 13:1,
I beheld another beast coming up out of
the earth. He had horns like a lamb and
spake as a dragon. Question,
where is this verse pointing to?
It's pointing to what land?
It's pointing to America.
>> Now, here's my next question. Is America
the beast?
In fact, let me do this.
Here is Ellen White, great controversy,
page 441.
He had two horns like a lamb. And by the
way, yeah, he had two horns like a lamb.
The lamblike horns indicate youth,
innocence, and gentleness,
fitly representing the character of the
United States when when presented to the
prophet as coming up in 1798. So she
calls it out, United States.
>> The Christian exiles who first fled to
America sought an asylum from royal
oppression and priestly intolerance, and
they determined to establish a
government upon the broad foundations of
civil and religious liberty. M
>> you guys let me ask it again. She said
here the land is America.
>> Is America
the beast from the earth? Yes or no?
>> The answer is
>> no. It is only the place
where we are to look for the entity
that will dominate in America.
>> And what is that entity?
It is apostate
Protestantism.
>> America is the where, but it is not the
who.
Everybody put a 10 in the chat if it was
worth your while to come on and learn
that tonight. We have only just begun,
y'all.
>> But just put a 10 in the chat if it was
worth your while to come on and to learn
that tonight.
>> You can still be patriotic
>> and acknowledge that this beast from the
earth
>> is bad. Mhm.
>> that this beast from the earth is a
power that is against God.
>> Yeah.
>> The text does not require you to hate
America. The text does not require you
to say America is evil because that's
not what the text is talking about. Mhm.
>> The reason that it speaks about this
beast that has horns like a lamb is it
is highlighting the Christian element
within America that will look Christlike
but act and speak like a dragon.
>> Because that's what the text says.
>> Are y'all ready for this?
Watch this now.
Here we go.
What is it that gives its kingdom to
this power?
Protestantism. Ton, can you read that?
>> While professing to have the temper.
>> Uh uh. Just start from the beginning.
Just start from the beginning.
>> What is it that gives it? What what is
it that gives its kingdom to this power?
Protestantism. A power which while
professing to have the temper and spirit
of a lamb and to be allied to heaven
speaks with the voice of a dragon. It is
moved by a power from beneath.
>> All right. So now we see that Ellen
White literally comes out and says,
"Apostate Protestantism
is
the beast with the horns of a lamb that
speaks like a dragon."
>> Yes, she said France is the place where
the beast from the abyss rose, but she
qualifies it and she's talking about
atheism which had its rise, its rise to
power in France. Yes, the beast from the
sea is the is is points to Rome.
>> And she says that, but she qualifies it
by saying we're talking about the
papacy.
>> Yes, America is the place where we're to
look for the rise of this beast from the
earth.
>> She says that, but she qualifies it by
saying it is actually apostate
Protestantism.
>> Are y'all following? Everybody put a
five in the chat. If you're following,
if this makes sense.
>> And the problem is many of us don't know
how to separate, we haven't separated
apostate Protestantism
from the land of America. Mhm.
>> So when we hear someone say, "Oh, this
beast has spoken like this beast that
that has the horns of a lamb has spoken
like a dragon since the beginning."
>> What are you saying about America? Stop.
>> We're talking about Protestantism,
>> apostate
Protestantism.
All right, I see a whole bunch of ones
in the chat. So, this is good. We are
now on the fives. I'm sorry.
>> I was like, I see a lot of fives. I
don't know where you're saying
>> in the chat. Okay. So, now we got to ask
ourselves a question.
Now, we got to ask ourselves a question.
Um, uh, this beast
when he speaks,
he speaks like a dragon. The text
doesn't say that the beast ever spoke as
something else and then as a dragon.
Doesn't say he spoke like a lamb and
then like a dragon.
>> It literally says he spoke as a dragon.
>> Now, here's where people get confused
again. Let's go back to the slides and
um let's notice this. Revelation 13
verse1 14. What does it mean when he
spoke when they when the text says he
spoke as a dragon? So in verse 14 it
says that this beast deceiveth them that
dwell on the earth by the means of those
miracles which he had power to do in the
sight of the fe the beast that is the
first beast saying to them
saying to them.
So now we have this beast actually
speaking.
The beast says something. What does the
beast say?
Saying to them that dwell on the earth
that they should make an image to the
beast which had the wound by a sword and
did live. And so
>> we understand this text, right,
>> to be pointing to the setting up the
legislation,
right? um
the the
when this nation officially becomes a
church state entity
>> and they're now setting up religious
laws
>> that are going to bring about
persecution.
>> So the text is telling us that the beast
is going to say this.
>> Yeah.
>> Which is very dragonlike.
>> It's persecution.
>> But here's the question. The question is
this.
Um,
is this the only thing the beast says?
What do y'all think? Put it in the chat.
Is Revelation 13:14 saying that this is
the only thing the beast ever says,
or is it highlighting that this will be
the main and most craziest thing the
beast says?
>> Did you get what I just asked?
>> Ask that again. want to phrase it. Okay.
>> Does the beast, if the beast arose
>> hundreds of years ago?
>> Mhm.
>> Does the beast just stay silent, doesn't
speak until the image of the beast is
set up?
>> I see what you're saying. Does it come
out at that one time?
>> Does a beast only say one thing ever in
life? Like, hey, I'm 100 years old now.
I'm 200 years old in America. D. And
then one day, he finally says, "Okay,
it's time for me to speak." Does the be
is the beast mute until
the passing of decrees that are going to
bring about the death? Right, the mark
of the beast. Is the beast mute or is
the Bible simply highlighting this is
the last and final and most dangerous
thing that the beast is going to do and
this is what I'm highlighting.
>> Okay. So, yeah. Well, I don't believe
that the beast is silent until that
time. Yeah,
>> that doesn't mean
>> we will have no reason
>> to believe that the beast just stays
silent,
>> right? That's not what the Bible says.
>> When the beast speaks, whenever it
speaks, it speaks like a dragon.
>> Are y'all following?
>> When it speaks, it speaks like a dragon.
So, we got to ask ourselves, we got two
options. Either the beast doesn't say
anything
for over 200 years
>> and then he finally speaks or the beast
has been speaking has been speaking as a
dragon.
>> Apostate Protestantism has been speaking
like a dragon.
Notice what I didn't say.
I didn't say the land of America because
that's not the highlight of the
prophecy.
>> The highlight of the prophecy is
Protestantism,
pretending to follow Christ,
>> pretending to be like Christ, pretending
to be gentle.
So either the beast was silent and then
still silent even now and will not speak
until
>> right
>> a Sunday law
>> or the beast has been speaking but has
not reached the crescendo the final
blasphemous thing that it says and does
till at the end of time. Mhm. But you're
not saying Protestantism knows that it's
being
>> Protestantism has no idea that right
>> it's being spoken about here.
>> That's what I mean. Okay. That's Yeah.
>> Okay. So again, option A. The beast is
silent. Apostate Protestantism has been
silent until it finally says make an
image to the beast. Or the beast has
been speaking as a dragon since its
inception. It's just that the voice gets
more and more
devious
as time goes on.
Now, if we're trying to defend the
beast, then what we're doing is
defending apostate Protestantism.
>> That's what we're actually defending.
And even though we don't realize that we
may be defending that, in defending
apostate Protestantism, we can actually
get to the place where we are finally so
connected with apostate Protestantism
that we're saying things like, "We are
going to help apostate Protestantism
Christianize
America. We're going to help your
various organizations, Turning Point
USA, and other organizations. We're
going to help you to accomplish your
mission." Advent is saying this
>> because
we don't rightly understand Revelation
chapter 13 11.
>> Are y'all following me?
>> I just want to make it clear for anyone
that may be confused just with that
statement right there because that could
be very possibly confusing to some. um
thinking when
inviting someone to get to know Jesus
is not apostate Protestants
Protestantism, right?
>> It's not.
>> We're going to talk about what apostate
We're going to talk about the dragon
voice shortly, y'all. So,
>> I I'm I'm a step ahead of you.
>> I'm following. Right. Just in case never
heard that term or ever thought
>> apostate Protestantism simply means
Protestants and we are Protestants but
Protestants who say they follow Jesus
but have a dragonlike spirit
>> have a dragonlike character. So, let's
So, for my job that I'm here to do,
let's let's be clear about what a
dragon-like spirit is, because a
dragon-like spirit is complete opposite
of the lamb. And a dragon-like spirit is
a spirit of Satan, and it'll want to
force that upon you.
>> The spirit of the lamb is like, "Here,
would you like this? Would you like to
come with me? Would you like to get to
know Jesus better and get to know him
personally for yourself? That
>> that is the spirit of the lamb.
>> But the dragon is a total opposite
spirit.
>> Yeah. So,
>> it's a spirit of force.
>> You've asked that and that's actually
leading right into my very next slide.
>> Okay.
>> Right into my very next slide.
So, here's a question then. What does it
mean to speak like a dragon? Let me ask
you a question. Who is a dragon? I'm
gonna take this off the screen for a
second. Who is the dragon? Everybody put
it in the chat. Put a put the answer in
the chat for me, please. Who is the
dragon?
>> Satan.
>> The dragon is Satan.
The dragon is Satan.
>> So, if we want to know
what it looks like to speak like a
dragon,
what better thing to do than to go look
at where the dragon speaks?
Let's look at where Satan speaks and
let's see what kind of things does Satan
say when he speaks. So let's go to the
screen and we are going to look at
something Jesus said here. Note what
Jesus said. Jesus said, "You are of your
father the devil and the lust of your
father will you do. He was a murderer
from the beginning and he abode not in
the truth because there is no truth in
him. when he speaketh a lie,
he speaketh of his own, for he is a liar
and the father of it. So let me ask you
a question. According to this text,
for um
for an entity
to speak,
let me fix that. for an entity to speak
like a dragon means that
when when the dragon speaks he lies.
>> So to speak like a dragon then would be
to do what?
>> Lie.
>> And lying why is lying wrong?
>> Because because God Jesus and God
they're a god of truth
>> and lying is
>> what? Yeah. Why is lying like wrong? How
do we know lying is wrong?
>> Because the ten commandments.
>> Because the
>> ten commandments.
>> The ten commandments. So when a dragon
speaks, the dragon breaks
>> the ten commandments.
>> The commandments.
>> Right.
>> Right. The dra dragon talk. When the
dragon speaks, he's a liar. Why is lying
wrong? Because lying is breaking the
commandments. In fact, in fact, you'll
see here that that the text actually
tells us,
>> but the dragon
>> in 1 John chapter 2:14,
>> he that saith, I know him and keepeth
not his commandments is a what?
>> A liar.
>> A liar, and the truth is not in him.
Okay.
>> But the dragon tries to be he knows that
verse.
>> We're going to come to that too.
So,
>> so he tries to do both.
We're going to come to that.
>> Not okay.
>> We're going to come to that.
To claim Christianity
>> and yet speak
against the commandments of God means
you're speaking what?
>> Lies.
>> The Bible says that's a liar. Mhm.
>> And if you're speaking lies, you are
speaking as a
>> dragon.
>> As a dragon. So then one thing we might
say to ourselves is, okay, so it what is
apostate Protestantism then? This
lamblike beast that speaks as a dragon.
Pastor, are you saying that the lamblike
beast is speaking lies about the
commandments of God? Yes. That would be
one way of demonstrating that this beast
that looks that has the horns of a lamb
when it speaks it's lying.
Y'all put a five in the chat if you
understand that. Do you understand what
I just said?
>> No, I understand what you just said, but
you know, but those that are taking on
that um belief system don't know that
they're lying.
>> Okay. So remember this now we're talking
about the system.
>> The system. Okay.
>> The system is teaching
things that are against the commandments
of God.
>> Right?
>> The system is lying.
>> The system speaks. It speaks from
inception.
>> All things speak from their inception.
Mhm.
>> So we can know, oh, the reason this
beast has the horns of a lamb
but speaks like a dragon is because it's
speaking lies. Oh, that's why it's
apostate Protestantism because it's
lying about something.
>> But let's pause for a second and let's
just go back to the screen and I want
you to notice something else. Something
else happened the very first time the
dragon spoke.
The Bible says in Genesis 3 1-4 1 and 4.
Now the serpent was more subtle than any
beast of the field which the Lord God
had made. And he said unto the woman,
"Yeah, has God said, you shall not eat
of every tree of the garden?" And the
serpent said unto the woman, "You shall"
So Eve answers the serpent. And then
when we jump down to verse four, the
serpent says to the woman, "You shall
not
surely
die."
You shall not surely die. Let me ask you
a question.
What is the very first lie
that the dragon spoke?
What is the very first lie that the
dragon spoke?
>> You should not surely die.
>> You shall not surely die. The
immortality of the soul. So let me ask
you a question. Might we say then
>> which is still the biggest deception in
the world. Whoever this beast is,
>> if we're looking at what it means to
speak like a dragon, one, we can see
that speaking like a dragon means
going against the commandments.
>> Two, speaking like a dragon means
promoting the first lie, which is the
immortality of the soul.
>> Are y'all following me?
>> Let's go back to the screen and let's
look at this verse. Revelation 12:9. And
the great dragon was cast out, that old
serpent called the devil and Satan,
which deceiveth the whole world. He was
cast out into the earth, and his angels
were cast out with him. And I heard a
loud voice in heaven, saying, "Now is
come salvation and strength, and the
kingdom of our God, and the power of his
Christ. For the accuser of our brethren
is cast down, which accused them before
our God day and night." Now
this
this word accused literally carries a
courtroom meaning with it. a prosecution
>> like you are legally guilty of doing
something and that accusation
that verbal accusation
says you are guilty and as a result of
you being guilty you should be punished
>> you should be persecuted
in other words the dragon accuses for
the purpose of persecution
legal persecution
Let me see if I got this slide on the
screen. Here we go. Can you guys see
this? Um,
the term accuser
means properly an accuser one who blames
another or charges another with crime.
>> Wow.
So
is speaking like a dragon
is speaking like a dragon does it
include a legal accusation
against God's people? A legal pers a
legal accusation that brings about
persecution.
>> Not a legal accusation.
>> Not legal as in lawful.
>> Okay. legal as in,
>> yeah, we're we're going to do this
through the court system.
>> Okay.
>> Rome
>> Rome persecuted the Christians,
>> right?
>> Through legal means.
>> The papacy,
>> but it wasn't legal per but it wasn't
legal. The papacy persecuted the
Christians through it was law. So, will
this happen at the end of time? The
answer is yes. That's what we talk about
saying to them at dawn on the earth that
they should make an image of the beast
and whosoever wouldn't bow down should
be killed.
>> God's people will be accused of crime
will be will be persecuted. So speaking
as a dragon then means number one
breaking the commandments of God.
>> Yeah.
>> Number two promoting the lie of the
immortality of the soul. Number three
persecuting God's people.
>> And then how about this one? How about
this?
I'm going to skip this for a second.
In fact, let me go ahead and read it.
The lamblike horn and the dragon voice
of the symbol point to a striking
contradiction between the profession and
the practice of this nation of the
nation thus represented. The speaking of
the nation is the action of its legal
and judicial authorities. By such
actions, it will give the lie to those
liberal and peaceful principles which is
has which it has put forth as the
foundation of its policy. The prediction
that it will speak as a dragon and
exercise all the power of the first
beast plainly fortetells of a
development of the spirit of intolerance
and persecution that was manifest by the
nations represented by the dragon and
the leopard beast. So
speaking like a dragon not only includes
persecution which we just saw. He's the
accuser of the brethren.
>> It also includes
going against the commandments of God.
>> It also includes speaking the lie of the
immortality of the soul. And then one
more thing. One more thing. Let's see if
I got this here.
Okay.
Wow. I don't have it in here.
>> Oh wow.
>> But let me just go ahead and remind you.
Let me let me do this.
So remember when Satan came to Jesus in
the gu in the uh in the wilderness
>> and he says command that this stone be
made bread.
>> Yeah.
>> And you know Jesus says you know get
behind me whatever. Um and then
he says throw yourself down for it is
written.
>> So he lied or well
>> what did he use?
>> He used the Bible.
>> Okay. So the dragon dragon speak is not
only going against the commandments of
God.
Not only speaking the lie of the
immortality of the soul. not only
persecuting
but using the Bible
to justify.
>> Everybody, y'all, put a five in the chat
if this makes sense.
>> To speak like a dragon involves at least
four things. commandment breaking,
>> persecuting through legal means,
>> the immortality of the soul,
>> and using lamblike language
>> to justify dragon speak
>> mercy.
I think you should make that slide big
and just sit there for a minute because
that's Yeah,
>> let me make the slide big and let it
just sit there for a minute.
commandment
that to speak like a dragon
means at least four things.
Number one,
commandment breaking, lying,
speaking lies, speaking against the
commandments of God. Number two,
speaking
the first lie, the immortality of the
soul. Number three, persecuting
through
legal means just as it did in Rome, just
as it did in the dark ages and just as
it will do at the end of time.
but also listen to me all using lamblike
language to justify
dragon speak.
In other words,
in other words,
part of speaking like a dragon is to
convince you that it's actually a lamb.
Part of speaking like a dragon, listen
to me you guys. Part of speaking like a
dragon is to convince you that it's
biblical, that it's Christian. Wait,
wait, wait, wait, wait. You thought I
said what? No, no, no, no. Let me use
the Bible to justify what I mean.
Speaking like a dragon
involves
lamblike language to explain away or
justify
dragon speak.
>> Mercy.
>> Y'all put a one in the chat if you if
you understand what I'm saying. So in
other words, you might be you might be
be
if you are of the mindset
where you're excusing
dragon talk
>> because it's couched in Christian
language.
>> Mercy.
>> There's a serious issue.
>> Yeah. And I think the problem, the
reason why I'm doing this tonight is
because a lot of people are no longer
hearing dragon talk. They're they're
unable to identify dragon talk because a
lot of it has been couched.
>> They can't Yeah. Christianifying it.
Yeah. Right.
>> So it's like, "Oh, no, no, no, no. You
thought that was you thought that was
dragon talk?" No.
What? Didn't you don't you hear? It's
couched in Bible language. Mhm.
>> So, this is good. And and here's the
thing, you guys. If you're unable to
hear the dragon talk that has been
occurring since the inception of the
beast,
it is most likely because
we've grown used to excusing the dragon
talk,
>> playing down the dragon talk of the
past. Yeah. So that when we hear it now,
we automatically downplay it
>> and justify it
and excuse it and say, "No, no, no, no,
no. What? You You think you're hearing a
dragon speak? No. I don't hear the
dragon in this."
>> Mhm.
>> What are you talking about?
>> Yeah.
>> You're You're taking the dragon out of
context.
When When the dragon said this, he
didn't mean that. Look, he put it in
Bible language.
Yeah.
>> And what I need you to understand,
beloved, is that what the enemy of souls
is trying to do is he's trying to get
you so used to dragon speak
that you begin to confuse it for
Christian speak.
>> And again, it's not a person, it's a
system.
>> Don't think a person, think a system.
>> Think a system.
Let me break this down for you.
We're going to go back to the screen.
>> Watch this, you guys. Watch how Ellen
White describes this through the two
great through the two great errors. The
immortality of the soul. Didn't we say
that was dragon speak?
>> And Sunday sacredness. Didn't we say
that was dragon speak? That's breaking
the law. That's speaking the law of
immortality of the soul. Mhm.
>> Satan will bring the people under his
deception. While the former lays the
foundation of spiritualism, the latter
creates a bond of sympathy with Rome.
>> Mercy.
>> The pro the Protestants of the United
States, not the United States, you guys.
The Protestants of the United States
will be foremost in stretching their
hand across the Gulf to grasp the hand
of spiritualism. That's the lie of the
immortality of the soul. They will reach
over the abyss to clas hands with the
Roman power. That's the changing of the
commandments. And under this three-fold
union, this country will follow in the
steps of Rome in trampling on the rights
of the conscience. That's the accuser of
the brethren. All of these things
combined represent the speaking of the
dragon.
>> His voice will be the speaking of the of
this
lamblike beast. Mhm.
>> The voice will be amplified at the end
of time, but he has been speaking like a
dragon since its inception.
How we doing so far?
We're doing
>> now. Now, I'm going to give you Let's
pause for a second.
Now, I'm going to give you the quote,
the one that many have been looking for.
Because for those of us who are like,
"No, the the lamb like beast has not yet
spoken like a dragon. It hasn't spoken
yet." I'm about to give you the quote.
Are you ready? Let's go. Let's go.
A, could you read that for me, please?
Prophecy represents Protestantism and
having lamblike
>> as
>> as Okay, sorry. As having lamblike
horns, but speaking like a dragon
already.
>> Stop. Can you read that word again?
>> Already.
>> All right. So, you just said already.
>> We are what?
>> Beginning to hear the voice of the
dragon.
>> Stop right there. Everybody look at the
date that this was written. Look at the
date that this was written. What is the
date that this was written? Put it in
the chat. The date is
189.
I want you to put the word already.
Put the word already in the chat.
Already.
Already. What does already mean?
>> It's already happening. means that in
1889 the beast was speaking like a this
beast with the horns of a lamb was
speaking like a dragon
>> at least in 1899 1889
>> the idea that the beast has not yet
spoken like a dragon
partially
it's almost like this we want to defend
America and you know be patriotic
>> and it's fine to do that But do not do
that at the expense of understanding
prophecy.
Because what happens is you then begin
to come to the place, and I'm going to
read that last sentence in a moment. Let
me just pull this off the screen for a
second. You then begin to come to the
place where you begin to excuse
>> or play on, I wasn't that bad in the
past.
>> That's not dragon talk. Mhm.
>> When when you look at the past and see
the things that have happened in America
and are unwilling to say that that was
dragon talk, man, you've just offended a
whole bunch of people
>> who whose
relatives
>> whose ancestors
were slaughtered at the hands of
Protestants. And to say this is not
dragon talk, this is not dragon speak
already sets you at a place where it's
like, wait, so you don't hold on. So you
think
you think that gay marriage now makes
the beast speak like a dragon?
That is what makes the beast speaks like
speak like a dragon. But all the stuff
led out by Protestants
during the 1800s and the 1700s, that's
not dragon speak,
>> you know.
>> I mean, it was bad. It was bad,
>> but that's not what the prophecies talk.
That's not the
>> And now you can begin to see what would
what would start to cause a rift
>> because you got one whole group of
people saying, "Wait a minute. So, what
happened to the Indians?
>> Yeah. Somebody said the Trail of Tears.
>> The Trail of Tears. That wasn't
>> just horrible.
>> That wasn't Dragon Speak. No, no, no.
>> But homosexual marriage, that's dragon
speak.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, it seems like we're being
selective.
>> What about slavery?
>> Obviously,
>> when we when we bypass those things
>> and said, "I wasn't dragon speak,
>> right?" that dragon speak only happens
when a certain political part is in
office. Now it's dragon speak. Now the
nation is speaking like a dragon.
>> So it goes back and forth.
>> We're putting a lot. When you do that,
you're putting a lot into the text.
>> A lot of yeast.
>> This is a problem.
>> This is a problem because what ends up
happening is that we inadvertently end
up defending the beast. And in def, I
don't know how the devil does it, but in
defending the beast, we inadvertently
find ourselves now saying the same
things as the beast.
>> We now find ourselves defending the
beast
and siding with the beast
>> and saying, "Hey, I'd rather cast my lot
in with the beast and who the beast says
our enemy is." Because the beast says
our enemies are those people and those
people and those people. And now we've
gotten so used to defending the beast
that we have begin to we begin to see
things just like the beast
and we embrace the beast and we
celebrate the beast and we go to beast
events and we do all kinds of things
with the beast
thinking
that we're showing that we are really
and truly Christians
because we stand with the beast.
Yeah, the beast does not uh it it always
has to have it always has to have you
against another group of people. It
doesn't unify. We're all sinners.
>> That's right.
>> But the beast is like,
>> "No,
>> some sinners.
>> These are the greater sinners. Sinners.
And your sins are less than their sins.
And so you have to be against them."
>> Yep.
>> You're better.
>> Which is wild.
>> Yeah. which is wild. So look, this is a
this there is a satanic force propelling
the Sunday movement, but it is
concealed. In other words, she was
saying as far as back then this movement
to enforce Sunday were echoes of the
beast speaking.
>> So let me ask you a question. Yes or no?
>> Does the be is the voice of the dragon
has the voice of the dragon been in
exist? Has the voice of the dragon been
a thing in the past?
>> Yes.
>> Absolutely, you guys. Why already?
She says,
>> and that was pinned in in 1889. But
>> let's read this in 1897.
>> That was late.
>> Let's read this.
>> Okay. Okay. The decree enforcing the
worship of this day is to go forth to
all the world. In a limited degree, it
has already gone forth. In several
places, the civil power is speaking with
the voice of a dragon just as the
heathen king spoke to the Hebrew
captives. Wow. 1897.
So, we have just now seen that yes, the
beast has been speaking like a dragon,
but it has not yet reached its climax.
It has not yet reached its full its full
potential.
>> It's still growing.
And beloved, what this does is it opens
up for us the crucial understanding that
if the beast has been speaking like a
dragon in the past, then we got to ask
ourselves, how else
how else was it speaking like a dragon?
>> Was it has the beast been going against
the commandments of God? Has this beast
been speaking the lie of the immortality
of the soul?
>> Has this beast persecuted other people?
>> Listen,
it's not a beast. It's not wicked
because it persecutes God's people.
>> It's wicked because it persecutes
people,
>> right?
>> It's not like, oh, when the when the
beast does it to us, that makes it evil.
But when the beast does it to some other
group, nah, that's not evil. I see
>> that mentality
is a is a dragonlike mentality, you
guys.
>> And that that
>> because what it says is I'm sorry.
>> No, no, no, no, no. You don't.
>> Well, I was just going to say that
>> um just thought process and principle
and is it comes right from Satan because
that's the first issue that happened to
him in heaven.
>> Yeah.
>> That he he was like, "Wait, no. I mean,
I'm better. I I'm better than I should
be able to be with Jesus and God in
these meetings. And you know what I'm
saying? Like he just self-exaltation
over other people.
>> Absolutely.
>> Instead of we're all equal. We're all in
this together.
>> And
it's not an issue until it deals with
me.
>> So many of us as Adventists have that
mentality.
>> No, that's not dragon speak. What
happened to to the slaves back there?
Not dragon speak. The Indians not dragon
speak. The 60 is not dragon speak,
>> but when the Sunday law, that's dragon
speak cuz that has to deal with me. And
so what it reveals is we don't have
empathy,
>> no
>> for when other people suffer. We don't
have empathy for other groups of people.
We don't have empathy.
>> And empathy is a Bible principle.
>> Empathy, believe it or not, you guys,
>> is a bi biblical principle
>> is a biblical principle.
>> Amen.
>> It is. It is. So the dragon, listen to
me y'all.
>> Empathy is Jesus.
>> Like you had to have
>> he was touched with the feelings of our
infirmity
>> and he and he came to earth to save us
and die. That that's empathy.
>> Yeah. So
what the dragon is trying to do is the
dragon is trying to train us to accept
dragon speak.
Mhm.
>> The dragon is trying to train us to
accept
the spirit of, hey,
it's not an issue until it it has to do
with me and my feelings and my
livelihood and my and guys, those who
enter the time of trouble with that
spirit will fall in the time of trouble.
Mhm.
>> The failure to recognize the voice of
the dragon from the past is leading to
the failure to recognize the voice of
the dragon right now.
>> We can't hear it. We can't hear the
anger. We can't hear the the the the the
venge, the venge, the vengeance. We
can't hear the the demeaning. We can't
hear that stuff. We just say, "Oh, oh,
you're what?
You hear dragon stuff in there?" I I
don't I listen to the whole I listen to
I don't
>> And the problem is
that we've grown so accustomed to
excusing dragon speak
>> that we can no longer identify it.
>> Nope.
>> We think it's Christian speak.
>> We think it's godly talk, you know.
rough present truth. Tell it as it is,
but it's dragon talk. And I'm going to
show you, beloved, what I'm talking
about. I'm not just pull I'm not just
pulling words out the air. I'm going to
demonstrate this to you. I'm going to
show you. Now, let's let's go ahead and
I want to I'm coming to some let come
on. Let's go back to the screen, y'all.
So, watch this. Now, remember remember
Let me read. Let me read. Ministers uh
testimonies to ministers and gospel
workers. The churches represented by
Babylon are represented as having fallen
from their spiritual state to become a
persecuting power against those who keep
the commandments of God and have the
testimony of Jesus. To John, this
persecuting power, what persecuting
power, pastor? the churches
represented by Babylon.
To John,
this persecuting power is represented as
having horns like a lamb, but as
speaking like a dragon.
Now you guys, I'mma leave this up on the
screen for a minute. If I were to ask
you, hey, um, you people watching,
according to this quote, who is the
beast that has the horns of a lamb and
speaks as a dragon? Your answer would be
what? Give me a name.
It would be
Babylon.
the churches.
Put a one in the chat if you see that
>> Babylon means confusion.
>> So Babylon, the fallen churches are the
be they make up the beast with the horns
of a lamb that speak as a dragon.
>> It's Babylon. So my question now is did
Babylon ever
>> It's perfect that it's confusion because
why would a a lamb and a dragon
>> Yeah.
>> They don't they don't go together. How
am I saying the horns of a lamb, but
it's speak I'm confused.
>> You it it
>> the beast claims to have the
characteristics of the lamb.
>> Are you a lamb or are you a dragon?
>> Are you lamb or you a dragon?
>> And if we're confused about it, there's
a problem.
>> Yeah.
>> We should not be confused about it.
>> We should be very clear about it.
>> So now we're being told that Babylon is
the beast with the horns of a lamb that
speaks as a dragon. It's right there on
the screen. I am not making it up, you
guys.
>> There is the verse. I mean there is the
text, there is the quote, there is the
quote.
So then
the question now for us is did Babylon
start off good and then eventually speak
as a dragon or does Babylon start off
fallen?
What do y'all think?
Cuz at first many of us were saying
>> the beast with the horns of a lamb that
speaks as a dragon starts off good
>> and it eventually in the future will
speak like a dragon. To say that is to
say
that Babylon
as it's given the name Babylon
>> which is a very specific time as it's
given the name Babylon
it
eventually becomes bad. It starts good
and eventually becomes bad.
>> But you guys, Babylon doesn't start
good. Mm-
>> That's why it's called Babylon.
>> Yeah.
>> We're not talking about the people.
>> We're talking about the system.
>> Yeah.
>> The system that says, "Hey, the rapture
is coming on, you know, this day, so get
ready." The system that tells people,
"Hey, you can be Christian and and
embibe and anger and and hatred and hate
the people and hate." The system
excuses dragonlike
behavior
>> and says, "Hey, but in the name of the
lamb, it's okay."
>> In the name of the lamb, it's all right
>> because you're doing it for the lamb.
So, it's okay to hate your enemy. It's
okay to demonize. It's okay
to do all these things. Mhm.
>> So
if we know that Babylon doesn't start
good and then become bad, the reason
it's given the name Babylon is because
it has now fallen.
>> So with that fallen now that it's fallen
doesn't start good.
It's always been fallen.
>> Yeah. Like someone said is fallen not
will fall.
>> That's right. So then what that means
>> like God would have said that very
clearly.
>> That's right.
>> You know, like you you can
>> Yeah. It will speak like a dragon in the
future.
>> You could be with it when it's acting
like a lamb,
>> right?
>> But it's going to soon turn into That's
not what the Bible verse says. God
doesn't say that.
>> That's right. So,
so with that in mind, you guys, here's
what we're about to do now. I'm about to
show you. Are y'all ready for this?
I'm about to show you
where how Ellen White describes
Babylon in one of the longest
descriptions. I think the longest
description she gives us Bab of Babylon.
I want you to listen to how she
describes Babylon, which when she
describes it, what is she actually
describing?
The beast with the horns of a lamb
>> that spake like a
>> dragon.
>> Dragon. Watch. There's going to be a
little read, so just just follow along.
Here we go. Here we go.
Early writings. Early writings. Here's
what she says. I saw the state. And by
the way, uh the reference here, you'll
see it at the end. You'll see it at the
end. Yeah. early writings which was
written in 1857 by the way. This is the
uh version of early writings. Listen
what she says. I saw the state of the
different churches since the second
angel proclaimed their fall. They have
grown they have been growing more and
more corrupt. Yet they bear the name of
being Christ followers. Doesn't that
sound like
>> horns of a lamb
>> but speaking like a dragon?
Mhm.
>> It is impossible to distinguish them
from the world. Their ministers take
their text for from the word but preach
smooth things, lies,
>> immortality of the soul.
>> Right?
>> The natural heart feels no objection to
this. It is only the spirit and power of
the truth and the salvation of Christ
that is hateful to the carnal heart.
There is nothing in the popular ministry
that stirs the wrath of Satan, makes the
sinner tremble, or applies to the heart
and conscience the fearful realities of
a judgment soon to come. Wicked men are
generally pleased with a form without
true godliness. a form of godliness
>> outside
>> looking like uh the principles of a lamb
but inside speaking like a dragon.
>> Said the angel, nothing less than the
whole armor of righteousness can
overcome and retain the victory of the
powers of darkness. Satan has taken full
possession of the churches
as a body.
The sayings and doings of men are dwelt
upon instead of the plain cutting truths
of the word of God. Said the angel, the
friendship of the and the spirit of the
world are at enmity with God. When truth
in its simplicity and strength as it is
in Jesus is brought to bear against the
spirit of the world, it awakens the
spirit of persecution at once. Many,
very many who profess to be Christians
have not known God. The the character of
the natural heart has not been changed
and the carnal mind remains at enmity
with God. They are Satan's own faithful
servants. Notwithstanding, they have
assumed another name. Hm.
>> The name of Christ, but speaking like a
dragon.
>> Reading on, I saw that since Jesus had
left the holy place of the heavenly
sanctuary and had entered within the
second veil, the churches were left as
were the Jews, and they have been
filling up with every unclean and
hateful bird. I saw great iniquity and
violence in the churches, yet they
profess to be Christians. Their
profession, their prayers, and their
exhortations are an abomination in the
sight of God. said the angel, "God will
not smell in their assemblies.
Selfishness, fraud, and deceit are
practiced by them without the reproving
of conscience." Let's keep reading. All
over all over and over all these evil
traits, they throw the cloak of
religion. I was shown the pride of the
nominal churches. God was not in their
thoughts, but their carnal minds
dwelling upon themselves. An innumerable
host of evil angels are spread are
spreading themselves over the whole
land. The churches and the religious
bodies are crowded with them and they
look upon the religious bodies with with
exaltation for the cloak of religion
covers their greatest the greatest
crimes and iniquities. Now
listen to this y'all.
All heaven beholds the indic with
indignation. Human beings the
workmanship of God reduced to the lowest
depths of degradation and placed on a
level with the brute creation by their
fellow men and professed followers of
that dare Savior whose compassion was
ever moved as he witnessed human woe
hardily engaged in this enormous and
grievious sin and deal in what?
slaves and souls of men.
>> Angels have recorded it all. It is
written in the book. The tears of the
pious bond men and bond women of fathers
and mothers and children, brothers and
sisters are all bottled up in heaven.
Agony, human agony is carried from place
to place and bought and sold. God will
restrain his anger but a little longer.
His anger burns against this nation and
especially against the religious bodies
who have sanctioned and have themselves
engaged in this terrible merchandise.
Such injustices,
such oppression, such suffering, many
professed followers of the meek and
lowly Jesus can witness with heartless
indifference.
And many of them can inflict with
hateful satisfaction all these
indescribable agonies themselves and yet
dare to worship God.
It is solemn mockery, and Satan exalts
over it and reproaches Jesus and his
angels with such inconsistency, saying,
"With hellish triumph, such are Christ's
followers."
>> These professed Christians read of the
sufferings of the martyrs, and tears
coarse down their cheeks. They wonder
that men could ever possess hearts so
hardened as to practice such inhumane
cruelties toward their fellow men. While
at the same time they hold their fellow
men in slavery. And this is not all.
They sever the ties of nature and cruy
oppress from daytoday their fellow men.
They can inflict the most inhuman
tortures with relentless cruelty which
would well compare with the cruelty of
papists and heathen exercised towards
Christ followers. I know I'm reading a
lot but I have to read it.
said the angel, "It will be more
tolerable for the heathen and for the
papist in the day of the execution of
God's judgment than for such men. The
cries and sufferings of the oppressed
have reached unto heaven, and angels
stand amazed at the hardened,
hard-hearted, untold, agonizing,
suffering man in the image of his maker
causes his fellow man."
said the angel, "The names of such are
written in blood, crossed with stripes,
and flooded with agonizing, burning
tears of suffering. God's anger will not
cease until he has caused the land of
light to drink the dregs of the cup of
his fury and until he has rewarded unto
Babylon double
spiritual gifts volume one
page 192 that is where the source is
from it is found in both early writings
and spiritual gifts you guys here is
what I want you to see here is what I
want you to understand
>> her greatest description of Babylon
was the hypocrisy of slavery
professing to be Christians and yet
imbued with the spirit of the dragon.
>> Go.
>> I just want to say and
and it's the hypocrisy part. I mean even
though it was child slavery and it was
very very bad. There's there are some
that will say, "Oh, other countries had
slavery and the hypocrisy part was not
there." Meaning they weren't it wasn't a
Christian nation. They weren't
confessing to be Christians.
>> That's right.
>> That piece.
>> That piece. That part.
>> That part.
>> Because all the slave masters went to
church.
>> That part.
>> They used the Bible to justify what they
were doing.
>> Yep. Yep.
Let's go to the screen. And here I want
you to see
>> because they can't find well we are we
are the Christian nation but you can't
find another nation.
>> That's right
such a such a thing.
>> The Bible these lofty principles we
worship the God of heaven.
>> Declaration of independence
>> but we
go
>> we're a Christian nation.
>> We go outside our front door and we
abuse
>> That's right.
>> humans.
>> That's right. To deny this dragon speak
is to excuse it. To deny that this is
dragon speak is to excuse it in the name
of patriotism.
>> Listen, America has good things. The
prophecy isn't talking about America.
It's not talking about the Declaration
of Independence. It's talking about the
hypocrisy that came with it. All men are
created equal except some men.
>> Um, Spirit of Prophecy, Volume 4, page
502.
The two-horned beast appears in two
phases with the gentleness of a lamb and
the fierceness of a dragon. This has to
some extent already been shown in the
consistency of sending forth to the
world the doctrine of the equality of
all men in respect to natural rights,
the right of life, liberty, and the
pursuit of happiness and upholding by
law all the evils of American slavery.
>> Also by professing to grant the
privilege to all to worship God
according to the dictates of their own
conscience. and then persecuting the
Baptists and the Quakers for following
their conscience conscientious
convictions. But this will be shown more
fully in the future when Congress shall
be called upon to make law.
>> This was in the appendence of great of
great of the great controversy.
>> It is evident. It is evident
that the dragon that the beast has been
speaking like a dragon since the
beginning.
>> But no, it is when the Sunday law is
passed in the future
>> that it ultimately speaks like a dragon.
That is the ultimate act because now
this is geared towards the whole world.
Mhm.
>> So in other words, what we're seeing,
guys, what we're seeing,
>> what we're seeing is that
>> the beginning of this nation, the things
we saw in the Christian world, in the
beginning of this nation, we're going to
see on a larger scale at the end of
time. everything, the persecution
in the name under the guise of the
Bible, the speaking of lies, the
immortality of the soul, all of those
things, what you see, what you saw in
the beginning of this nation and how the
slaves were were treated,
you're looking at Adventists at the end
of time.
>> Yeah.
So then it then it means something,
excuse me. And it's it's not really
having true empathy
looking at it in that way, in the other
way because it's only bad or it's only a
dragon when it when it affects me.
>> When it affects me, it's only a dragon.
>> And I'm thinking that the dragon's also
speaking currently because it's trying
to
wipe history, if you will. It doesn't
want
>> the dragon gener the new the generations
now to understand
>> it will history the true history
>> it will couch its its mess
>> in Bible
>> it wants to erase its past
>> yeah not even erase it reframe it
>> well that it's not
>> that it wasn't
>> reframe it that wasn't that bad
>> that's how the dragon speaks you guys
all right
I hope y'all for following. Watch. Let's
go back to the screen. Let's go back to
the screen. So So here we go. Through
pro though professing to be followers of
God of the lamb of God, men become
imbued with the spirit of the dragon. So
I want you to see what she does here.
Now what she does here is she
changes out voice of the dragon
>> for spirit of the dragon.
>> It's one and the same thing. Mhm.
>> The voice of the dragon is the spirit of
the dragon.
>> Though professing to be followers of the
lamb of God, men become imbued with the
spirit of the dragon.
>> They profess to be meek and humble, but
they speak and legislate with the spirit
of Satan, showing by their actions that
they are the opposite of what they
profess to be. their lamb. This lamblike
power
unites with the dragon in making war
upon those who keep the commandments of
God and have the testimony of J. That's
powerful there, guys.
>> What we're seeing here is that this
actually boils down to character.
Do you look like a lamb on the outside
>> but have hate on your heart in your
heart on the inside?
Do you hate those evil, ungodly people?
Do you hate the wicked? The wicked,
corrupt, evil, dark, destructive,
wicked, wicked, wicked, evil, satanic
people that you want to label as this
group of people. Do you hate them?
>> No. No. No. No. I don't hate them. I
just speak about them with hate.
The dragon will always justify hatred.
And there's a comment in the chat that's
saying before slavery they killed Native
American Indians. And it's the same
thing. It's like but they but as
Christians they did that.
>> Y as Christians.
>> As Christians
>> where other nations did not claim to be
Christians.
>> Yeah. So now now I want to show you what
our pioneers taught about this lamblike
beast. Our pioneers Uriah Smith, JN
Andrews, Lboro, James White, what they
taught
>> about this prophecy. We're just going to
read for a little bit. So let's follow.
This is uh review and herald November
8th, 1853. He spake as a dragon. The
dragon spirit is a persecuting warlike
spirit.
Therefore, free and bond or sla slaves
and souls of men are under the power of
this two-horned beast. And where can
there be found a more striking striking
resemblance than in American bond
slavery fostered by Babylon and the
states?
Let's go to the next one.
We say we bid all reforms, Godspeed, but
some are laboring for reforms which they
will never see accomplished. as much as
anyone from our from our from our very
own soul. We detest and abhore the foul
blot of our country slavery and our
sympathies are with those in whose
hearts burn the love of freedom and who
would desire to see the bondman loose
from his chains.
But he who expects to see this land
freed entirely from this curse or even
to see slavery contend contendedly
confined confine itself within certain
limits we can but regard as laboring
under a false hope. For the
characteristic which the prophetic
pencil has given to the two-horned
beast, a symbol of our country, is that
he shall speak as a dragon. Not that
slavery alone constitutes the dragon
voice, but we must take with it its
prime mover, that infernal spirit
that is even now on the plains of
Kansas, burning the homes of free men to
the ground and driving out their inmates
robbed and insulted, and which would
which but recently prompted a brutal
assault upon the senator in the very
halls of Congress. It goes on to say,
same quote,
prophecy gives us no ground to hope for
reform. Here the beast speaks like a
dragon. People may caress him never so
fondly or threaten him never so
fiercely. They cannot reform his mouth.
He will speak like a dragon still. The
prophecy does not say that at first he
spake like a dragon, but at length
reformed his speech and breath and
breathed forth a just and Christlike
spirit. His future history presents no
redeeming feature. He will continue to
bellow forth his dragon voice till he
shall be cast into the burning flame.
And the remnant whom he will persecute
shall take their stand of victory on
Mount Zion with the lamb.
You guys, that is a powerful powerful
statement.
That's powerful y'all. These are our
pioneers.
Adventist review in here on March 19th,
1857.
Is the inquiry now raised wherein the
two-horned beast has spoken like this?
Wherein our government has issued
wherein our government has issued
unrighteous decrees contrary to its
profession? We will notice we do not
claim that the dragon voice is yet fully
developed and the prophecy fully carried
out in this respect.
>> But enough has been heard heard
heard to identify the beast and to
establish a precedent from which we are
justified in expecting almost any
result.
Says the Declaration of Independence. We
hold these truths to be self-evident
that all men are created equal, that
they are endowed by their creator with
with certain unalienable rights, that
among these are life, liberty, and the
pursuit of happiness. And yet the same
government that utters this sentiment in
the very face of this declaration will
hold in abject servitude over 3,200,000
of human beings, rob them of those
rights which they which they acknowledge
that all men are endowed by their
creator. and write out a base denial of
all their fair professions in characters
of blood.
You guys, it goes on and on. I'm going
to give you my slides, but it goes on.
John Andrews,
John Lboro,
Uriah Smith,
it goes on and on and on and on and on
and on and it almost makes you wonder JH
Wagner. It almost makes you wonder how
in the world did we get to the place
where we stopped preaching this?
It was very clear to our founding
fathers. I mean, it the history shows um
how they would speak out against
slavery. They had an anti-slavery
movement, literally risking their lives.
Um and so it it was very clear to them,
very clear,
>> very clear.
So then
I want you guys to see and understand
what I mean when I talk about the dragon
voice.
So
this
Let's see here. I just want to get the
source real quick. Okay,
here we go.
Oh, my bad. I kind of started a little
bit uh later in this. Okay, so here is
the Bible view of slavery written by uh
John Hopkins. And this was actually
written in I believe it was 1817.
It's not on my slide here, but when I
I'm gonna edit this slide, put the right
date on it, and I want you to notice
this. We're talking about the dragon
voice. Listen to this. This is his
defense of slavery. And I want you to
listen. The slavery of the negro race as
maintained in the southern states
appears to me fully authorized in both
the old and new testaments which as
written uh as which as a written word of
God afforded the duly infallible
standard of moral rights and
obligations. And thus by the southern
sli slaves becoming Christianized
through slavery, the wisdom and goodness
of God are vindicated in the sanction
which his word has given. And the
sentence originally passed upon Canaan
as a curse has been converted into a
blessing. Let me pause for a second, you
guys.
>> A blessing for America.
>> A blessing for the slaves.
Now
>> they're saying a blessing for America
because the slaves built America and
they for free. But I mean that's what
>> they're saying a blessing for the
slaves.
>> How is it a blessing for the slaves?
>> Because they got they were
Christianized.
>> Okay.
>> All right. So you guys listen now,
listen now, listen. Let's say that we're
living back in this time
>> and um someone says, "Hey man, this guy
is racist
and you're like because he says he backs
slavery and then you say, whoa, whoa,
hold on, hold on. Have you read his Have
you read his statement? Let me show you
what the statement says. This guy's a
Christian. I don't know what you're
talking about." The guy says here, here,
let's put it back up on the screen.
Listen to what he says. He says, "The
slavery of the negro race as maintained
in the southern states appear to be
fully authorized in both the old and new
testaments, which as the written word of
God afforded the duly infallible
standard of moral rights, rights, and
obligation." And thus, by the southern
slaves becoming Christianized through
slavery, the wisdom and goodness of God
are vindicated. Come on. This guy, hold
on, hold on. This guy is a Christian
>> and he's rejoic he's not
>> blasting I mean he's not like saying
yes he's saying that slavery wasn't was
was was a thing but he's saying because
God's will was being accomplished
through it
>> is this the same John Hopkins that
>> I don't think so
>> the thought okay I was just thinking
>> it could be I don't know I'm actually
just noticing the name
>> his name is John Hopkins
>> yeah but but the argument here is listen
this this was in the name of God
>> I'm using Bible language
to show you that yes, I'm talking about
slavery and yes, I believe slavery is a
good thing,
>> but I'm being real here. Like, this was
God orchestrating this to bring about
the Christianization of the slaves, you
guys. Isn't that a good thing? I don't
have hate in my heart. Where are you
getting this dragon talk from? I'm
>> So, when you hear this type of thought
process now, this it was
>> Don't go there yet. But but I
>> I'm building my brain is going there.
>> Your brain is going there. I get
>> but I'm just I want you to see
>> the hypocrisy
that Christianity has always in the
context of
>> basically what you hear now is not new.
>> What you hear now
>> is not new.
>> Is not new. Let's go back to the screen.
It's not finished. He goes on to say
again and again, "Under the rule of the
scriptures and the Constitution of the
United States, the Negro belongs to an
inferior race." Well, I'm not saying
anything offensive. I'm just This is the
truth. It's it's Bible. It's fact.
>> Yes, that's
>> it's just fact. I'm not being mean or
anything. I mean, how how nicely do you
want me to say? It's just fact.
>> The Negro belongs to an inferior race
which the law did not presume to be
fitted for freedom at any age. And
finally, God in his wisdom. No. So no,
not the same. God in his wisdom and
providence caused the patriarch Noah to
redirect the ne uh redirect the negro
should he be should be that the negro
should be the servant of servants to the
posterity of Jaff. This then is the
position that the negro slavery of the
southern states
is justified
in holy scripture.
See that guys?
>> It's Bible.
We're just speaking the truth and people
don't like the Christian truth.
>> Where is he?
>> People don't like the Christian truth.
This is just I'm just speaking. So this
is what they were doing back then.
>> We have the right to do this by God.
>> Yeah.
>> So here's another one. This one is
written by Dress by Henry Drestler 1818.
The assertion which the writers
undertake to prove from holy scripture
is that as set forth by himself, the
slavery of the negro race as maintained
in the s in the southern states appear
to me. Oh, I'm sorry. This is actually
the same thing. I just got it up there
twice. Got up there twice.
Um. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So, so I'm gonna
read another one to you. Another one to
you. Here we go. Yes, you guys will get
all of these quotes.
Okay. Here is an address by the general
assemb assembly to all the churches of
Jesus Christ throughout the earth by
James H. Thornell. And I'm just taking a
couple of quotes here. The question then
is brought within a narrow compass. Do
the scriptures directly or indirectly
condemn slavery as a sin? If they do
not, the dispute is ended. For the
church, without forfeiting her
character, dares not go beyond them.
Now we venture to assert that if men had
drawn their conclusion upon this subject
only from the Bible, it would no more
have entered into any human head to
denounce slavery as a sin than to
denounce monarchy, aristocracy, or
poverty. The truth is men have listened
to what they falsely considered as
primitive in intuitions or as necessary
deductions from primitive cognitions and
then have gone to the Bible to confirm
the crochets of their vain philosophy.
In other words, it's vain philosophy
that slavery isn't permissible by God
and that southern slaves should have
some some freedom. That's you're
bringing philosophy into this. We got to
go by the Bible and the Bible only.
>> They have gone there to determine to
find a particular result and the
consequence is that they leave with
having made instead of of having
interpreted scripture.
>> Slavery is no new thing. It has not only
existed for ages in the world, but it
has existed under every dispensation of
the covenant of grace in the church of
God. Indeed, the first organization of
the church as a vis as a visible
society, separate and dis separate and
distinct from the unbelieving world was
inaugurated in the family of a
slaveholder. Among
the very first persons to whom the seal
of circumcision was affixed were the
slaves of the father of the faithful.
Some born in his house and others
brought with his money. Slavery again
reappears under the law. God sanctioned
it in the first table of the decalogue.
And Moses treats it as an institution to
be regulated, not abolished, legitimated
and not condemned. We come down to the
age of the New Testament and we find it
again in the churches founded by the
apostles under the plenary inspiration
of the Holy Ghost. These facts are
utterly amazing. If slavery is the
enormous sin which its enemies presented
to be,
>> it will not do to say that the
scriptures have treated it only in a
general incidental way without any clear
implications as to its moral character.
Moses surely made it the subject of
express and positive legislation. And
the apostles are equally explicit in in
calculating the duties which spring from
both sides of the relation. They treat
slaves as bound to obey and incalculate
obedience as an office of religion, a
thing wholly self-contradictory if the
authority exercised over them were
unlawful and iniquitous.
>> And you did a study a while back um I
don't know how long it was. It's been
with within the last four years in
describing slavery in the Bible
and what that looked like.
>> Y
>> So I just
>> Yeah, that's that's a whole
>> I know that's a whole another thing. I'm
not trying to go there now.
>> It's not what the slave masters were
saying.
>> Yes. Absolutely. Right. Right. Right.
Right.
>> So here's what I want you guys to
understand here.
Dragon talk
back then was excusing the sin of
slavery. It was excusing racism.
Are y'all following me?
Dragon talk
was excusing racist ideologies.
>> There's more I can read here,
>> but I think you all get the point. It's
interesting when you hear these concepts
today, you think these were original for
today and they weren't.
>> Yep.
>> People were saying this that long ago.
>> The same thing.
>> All right. Now, are y'all ready for the
bomb?
Just put a one in the chat if you're
ready for the bomb
because what I'm about to share with
you, many of you may have never heard
before.
Um,
I had not heard it before. I've heard it
before.
>> I've heard,
>> but I didn't know the whole story behind
it.
>> I've heard parts of it.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> But I didn't understand it.
>> Yeah.
>> My mom would say it.
>> So you guys listen, if we if we don't
understand the dragon speak from the
past, when we hear it in the future,
we're not going to recognize it either
either.
And a lot of us are hearing dragon speak
right in our faces
and we see
we don't understand it as dragon talk.
>> Judah Wooda.
>> I know. I thought it was Sorry guys. Our
our our sevenyear-old nephew
>> my brother's son
>> just went on and said hi Uncle Al.
>> Just said hi Uncle Al.
>> Hi Judah. And Judah it is
>> Judah. It is almost 11. It's almost 11
where you are. It's time to go to bed.
But okay.
>> All right.
>> Back to this.
>> All right, Judah. We'll talk later.
Okay. So,
if we don't understand and cannot
recognize dragon speak from the past,
if we do not understand and cannot
you're like,
>> we are not going to recognize dragon
speak in the present. And we certainly
will not recognize it in the future. In
fact, we will join it in the future. And
this is why it is so important for us to
rightly understand Revelation 13 11.
Listen to me y'all.
Here is what I'm about to share with
you.
>> Good night, Judah. He said, "Okay."
>> All right.
>> And byebye.
>> Very good.
>> Okay.
Here we go. In 1895,
Ellen White is involved in in uh in a
series of meetings that
up until that point, she wanted to keep
it. She did not speak on it. And when
she spoke on it, she told the people
that were there not to publish what she
had just said.
Y'all put a 10 in the chat if that blows
you away right now. Put a 10 in the chat
if you're like, "Wait, what? Ellen White
spoke about something and then told the
people not to publish it, not to make it
public.
What are you talking about, pastor?"
>> Let's give them time for the put their
tens in the chat.
>> Yeah.
So here is here is part of a letter from
from part of that meeting.
She says this of some of these things I
could speak because at sunundry times
and in diverse places many things have
been presented to me as my brethren read
the selections from letters. I knew what
to say to them for this matter had been
presented to me again and again. I have
not felt at liberty to write out the
matter until now.
This is 1895.
Something has been on her mind and on
her heart and she had not felt at
liberty to write it out until now. And
I'm going to show you a few a few uh
slides from now that at the end of this
she says do not publish this. Give it to
the workers that are working in this
field, but do not publish this to the
public because they're not
ready.
Here's what she said in that meeting.
Slavery
will again be revived in the in the
southern states for the spirit of
slavery still lives.
Let me pause on that for a second
in 1895.
So slavery came to an end in the 1860s.
We are now in 1895.
And Ellen White in 1895
said, "Slavery
will again be revived
in the southern states for the spirit of
slavery still lives."
I believe this quote was not made. No, I
could be wrong on this, but I believe
this quote, in fact, there's a book, a
little book that the
white estates put out in 2018,
and this is after all of the Law White
writings were made available.
>> And this statement, this statement was
found, and people started writing into
the white estates, and they put together
a little pamphlet called slavery, will
it be revived
>> again? Please go read that pamphlet. And
like Carrie said, this is 30 years after
the Civil War.
>> This is 30 years after the Civil War.
And Ellen White says the
>> which makes sense why she's like, don't
publish this, right? Like that was the
most bloodiest war.
>> Yeah. So the context the context of this
meeting was this. as Adventists were now
doing work in the southern field,
>> they were running into this problem of
how do we, you know, when when when the
black person finds out about the
Sabbath, you know, some of them are
going out and like intensely working on
Sundays to demonstrate that they are
Sabbathke keepers and that they are, you
know, that they're following the true
way. and
their white neighbors, their white
counterparts are killing them.
And I don't know why is like she begins
to speak to this issue and she's talking
about the need for caution. Even though
slavery has been outlawed, the spirit,
she says, is still alive. Now, let me
ask you a question. If the spirit was
still alive then and it was part of the
dragon spirit of this beast with the
horns of a lamb that speaks as a dragon.
How many of you think that the beast has
been reformed? Put a one in the chat if
you think the beast has been reformed.
The beast knows better. Now
remember, we're talking about the
system. We're not talking about that
individual or that. We're talking about
the system as a whole and the principle.
She says the spirit of slavery
still lives on.
>> Meaning there is still hypocrisy
in the Christian churches. These
churches that claim to follow Jesus but
are still harboring the spirit of
racism.
Now I found something very interesting
these days that we know that in the
Bible all sins from the very beginning
of time
>> are still sins and as time goes on we
know that all sins are going to get
worse.
>> We know that.
>> We know that all sin is going to
increase. But for a lot of people the
sin of racism got played out. It's no
longer a sin anymore because it doesn't
exist anymore.
like people some people just stopped
thinking that they were better than
>> than others.
>> Racism I'm saying like one race is more
superior than others.
>> Yeah. We they just you know racism is
gone now. Like that sin Satan couldn't
keep that one going. You know the people
wisened up and you know that's no longer
an issue now. So we're good. we don't
have to talk about racism when the very
basis
>> even though it's as old as
>> it's as old as whatever
>> the beginning of time
>> but suddenly now this one
>> doesn't exist anymore and so when when
if racism is brought up there's this
almost visceral reaction of
what do you mean racism I'm not talking
about accusing people of being or you're
racist you're that's not what I'm saying
but I'm saying that the idea that racism
is still an actual sin that still
exists.
>> The spirit of racism,
>> the spirit of racism still exists. It's
like, what are you talking about?
>> What do you mean?
>> In 1895,
listen. Ah, let me finish reading. So
she goes on to say, she goes on to say
that therefore it will not do it will
not do for those who labor among the
colored people to preach the truth as
boldly and openly as they would be free
to do in other places. Okay. So
go to the next slide. And and in that
same discussion, she says this, "Judges
and jurors, lawyers and citizens would,
if they had a chance, bring decisions
which would bind about them rights which
would cause much suffering not only to
the ones whom they turn guilty of
breaking the laws of their state, but
all the color people everywhere would be
placed in a position of surveillance and
under a cruel treatment. by the white
people. That would be no less than
slavery.
Now you guys listen,
she's not talking about all white
people.
She's not.
>> This is not a condemnation on all. What
she's saying is that the spirit of
racism was still alive in the hearts of
many of those people in the south.
it it was still there
>> as a prophet. So, we can say, "Ah, no,
she wasn't a prophet on this one."
>> Or we can say, "Yeah, we believe she's a
prophet, and we believe she's telling
the truth, and we believe what she said,
>> 1895.
Let's go back. I want to show you that
there. Listen, there's more coming. Let
me show you something. In the month of
April, a Now, this is a dip. This is not
the same meeting, but listen to what she
says here. In the month of April, a
scene in the southern field was
presented before me. Oh, what
destruction? What destitution was there?
What need of help? In March, there had
been some confusion in the south which I
could not explain. Our people were in
trouble with the southerners who were
making efforts to hinder the work from
being established.
Thousands of the colored people cannot
read and therefore cannot study the word
of God for themselves. And there are
very many among the white people who do
not want us to give assistance to this
poor, ignorant, half-clad, half-fed
people. They do not want them to be
taught how to work, how to become self-
sustaining, and they are seeking to
revive
the spirit of slavery in the South.
What year is that, Aante?
>> 1899.
1899.
Let me keep reading. While I was
speaking, same same uh uh quote. While I
was speaking, some voices were raised
saying, "We have been told that these
great precautions are not necessary and
that altogether too much has been made
has been said in regard to the dangers
existing in the South." In other words,
they're like, "Look, slaveryy's over.
Racism is done. What are you talking
about, Ellen?
>> It's 1899.
>> It's 1899. This is 30 30 years ago, 40
years ago. I turned to the speakers and
said, "You do not understand the
elements to be dealt with in the in the
southern field. As soon as an effort is
made to educate and uplift these people
who have so long been held in ignorance
and slavery, the jealousy of the whites
is aroused."
>> Uh, it will not do to work that field
with the same freedom that you would
bring into your work in the northern
states. On many subjects a discrete
silence must be maintained or a state of
things will be brought against brought
about which will close the field against
us. Those who apprehend no danger and
think they can work on the same lines as
the south in as in the north have no
real wisdom. In the south the spirit of
slavery is not eradicated. It has only
been smothered
for a short time.
>> You guys, I need you to understand
what it's not a coincidence that right
now in America there's so much talk
about race.
In our church, there's so much talk
about it's not a coincidence. And after
reading the these statements from Ellen
White, it's like, okay, yeah, that's one
of the things the devil's going to try
to use to bring about disorder and
separation in God's church.
>> Wow.
Wow. Listen to this.
their desire or the the desire to show
their mastery masterly authority over
the blacks is still burning in the
hearts of many who claim to be
Christians but whose lives declare that
they are standing under the black banner
of the great apostate horns like a lamb
speak like a dragon. When the whites
commit crimes, they are often allowed to
go unconddemned. While for the same
transgressions, the blacks, ignorant,
debased, knowing nothing of the word of
God, and scarcely knowing their right
hand from their left, are treated worse
than brutes.
Now,
in case you guys think that Ellen White
is alive right now,
and it's talking about right now, Ellen
White
died in the early 1900s,
>> 1915.
You would think she was talking about
what's going on right now
and yet she's talking about this
>> in the 1800s
same crime, different treatment
happening.
this kind of
wickedness happening in the hearts of
professed
Christians.
Let's keep going.
We're going to go back to the screen.
The demon of passion is let loose and
all the sufferings that can be visited
that can be devised is instituted
against them. Will not God judge for
these things? As surely as the whites
have brought their inhuman cruelty to
bear upon the Negroes, so surely will
God's vengeance fall upon them. Again,
1899.
And then she says this, "Satan is doing
his best to block the way to the
progress of the message. He is putting
forth efforts to bring about the
enactment of a Sunday law which will
result in slavery in the southern field
and will close the door to the
observance of the true Sabbath which God
has given to men to keep holy. Do y'all
see this? This is 1909.
She said the Sunday law
will bring back slavery
in the southern field.
I had to be quiet all this time because
I saw people in the chat saying what I
originally said like, "Oh yeah, Jim,
she's Jim Crow and those that time and
this makes you think, no, that's not
what she was talking about."
>> Which means
That racism is still a part of this
beast with which has horns of a lamb but
speaks like a dragon
>> you guys.
>> This is crazy.
>> Yeah.
>> This is like what? Mhm.
>> It's not a coincidence what's going on
in our world today. It's not a
coincidence of what's happening in
America today. And what I'm trying to
tell you is that
>> in that Christian world,
>> there is a lot of crookedness going on
underneath under the disguise of
Christianity.
>> And as Adventists, we of all people
ought not to be a part of it. No,
>> we ought to be the people standing
together shouldertosh shoulder.
>> Black man, white man, Chinese man,
Asian, standing against
>> this beast that appears with the horns
of a lamb, but is actually dragonlike in
spirit
and in action.
you know, and when I mean, you shared
this study with me this week and I was
like blown away. But you know, thinking
about it as like back in when you think
about back to the basics and you're and
um the p what has to happen um for every
for
the world to come into
an agreement in one space like
>> the you know Jesus I mean Satan
returning as Jesus and bringing back
dead loved ones and the dead loved ones
telling us hey you're wrong this this
and that and the other. So it would make
So this part
makes sense as well. Like
you know you Sabbathkeeping Christians
aren't willing to to um give up Sabbath
and worship on Sunday even with Jesus
coming back and saying this was not
right. The dead loved ones saying that.
And so treated as slaves.
>> That's what I'm saying. So
>> white people
>> it's not it's not that right now without
putting those pieces together then it's
like what? What do you mean slavery? No.
Putting those things together, it's not
it's not hard at all to be like, "Oh,
yeah. Well, Jesus came back and said
that this is not you're not supposed to
be worshiping on this day." So, of
course, you're going to be slaves now.
>> Yep. You're going to be in you're going
to be imprisoned. You're going to be
treated.
>> Some are going to be in prison. Some be
enslaved. Yes.
>> And that makes sense.
>> And involved in that
>> is the issue of racism still dwelling in
the hearts of many people,
>> right?
You guys,
this
this needs to be addressed. Like, we
need to understand this as a church. But
>> there's going to be some white slaves,
too. Then
too.
>> I'm saying because they're not I mean,
>> there's going to be Chinese going. Yeah.
There's going to be all different kind
of slaves.
>> And now it's going to be like then it's
going to be like, okay, now we get what
y'all went through,
>> right?
Mercy.
>> Unfortunately, some will not be slaves
because some will grow to see exactly
what the beast sees. Some will grow to
understand and see things in the way the
beasts see things.
>> Yeah,
>> Mondo is very heavy.
>> Says it's very heavy. Yeah, it is.
Mondo, listen to this. It will be
impossible to adjust all matters
regarding the color question. Let me put
up on the screen.
It will be impossible to adjust all
matters regarding the color question in
accordance with the Lord's order until
those who believe the truth are so
closely united with Christ that they are
one with him. Both the white and the
colored members of our church need to be
converted. Bomb explosion. Wow. Do you
see what she just said?
>> Yeah. She just said, "Both the white
people and the black people
>> in our church need to be converted.
>> The black people
need to forgive
>> and the white people need to love
>> because there was anger. Y'all are the
ones that that that enslaved us." She
says,
"In our church,
>> we can't even deal with the situation,
right? Because our own members need to
be converted. How are we going to go out
there to the world and tell them what
they're doing is wrong
>> when we're denying that it still exists
in the church?"
>> Yeah.
>> Both.
>> Listen to this. Letter 105 1904. There
are some of both classes who are
unreasonable and when the color question
is agitated, they manifest unsanctified,
unconverted traits of character. Why do
you keep bringing up racism?
>> You're a racist.
You keep bringing up racism, you're a
racist. You keep bringing up racism,
you're a racist. You keep bringing up
racism, you're a racist.
There are some of both classes who are
unreasonable when the color question is
agitated. They manifest unsanctified,
unconverted traits of character.
Quarrelome elements are easily aroused
in those who, because they have never
learned to wear the yoke of Christ, are
opinionated and obstinate. In such
self-clamor with an unsanctified
determination for in such self-clammers
with an unsanctified determination for
supremacy.
Because if you don't have empathy now
and you think that that's a
madeup emotion,
then you're definitely not going to
carry that into
>> Yeah.
>> the time of trouble.
>> You're not
>> when
>> because you don't have it now. You can't
you wouldn't carry it there.
You guys, this is absolutely crucial to
understand that
>> if we don't see what the what the
lamblike beast has been doing in the
past,
>> denying something, denying something is
not you can't have empathy if you deny
something even that
>> it wasn't that bad or it doesn't or it
doesn't exist anymore or
>> oh, you're it's just a talking point,
right?
>> Oh, it's just the
The lack
of conversion
is the reason these issues are still
going on. Yet, Ellen White was very
brave. And now, hold on. I haven't even
showed you.
Listen to this.
She says they cannot go to the south and
present the real facts in reference to
Sunday keeping because
because the mark of the beast and being
the mark of the beast and encouraged
color people to work on Sunday. For the
same spirit that held the color people
in slavery is not dead but alive today
alive today and ready to spring into
activity. The same spirit of oppression
is still cherished in the minds of many
of the white people of the south and
will it and will reveal itself in cruel
deeds which are the manifestation of
their religious zeal. Religious zeal.
>> Some will oppose in every possible way
any action which has a tendency to
uplift the colored race and teach them
to be self- sustaining.
And y'all get ready for this one. Let
all be warned. Let the instruction be
given to this much oppressed people that
the keeping of the Sabbath does not
necessitate their working on Sunday. For
if they should do this, they would have
instigated against them all the powers
of the white population who are
transgressors of the law of God. Church
members and priests and rulers will
combine to organize secret societies to
work in their land to whip, imprison,
and destroy the lives of the colored
people. History will be repeated.
1895,
the Kucks Clan, which started in the
1860s,
died out by 1874.
In 1895,
Ellen White said, "Secret societies will
be organized to whip, imprison, and
destroy." A secret society is where you
don't want people to see your identity.
Mercy.
>> The Ku Klux Clan was revived
>> in the 19 early 1900s, 1905 06 07
somewhere around there, maybe even 1910.
The Ku Klux Klux Clan, which is a secret
society, was revived where they beat and
whipped and imprisoned.
Y'all going to tell me she's not a
prophet?
And if she was right there, do you think
the spirit of the dragon has died?
Do you think the spirit of the dragon
has? No, it hasn't died. It's just
become more deceptive.
>> It's harder to point out now because
the dragon speak has gotten better and
better and better and better.
She closes this council and says, "I
would not advise that this be published
in our papers, but let the workers have
it in leaflets and let them keep their
own councils."
It's almost as if she was like, "Our
people are still
almost so unconverted
>> that if they read what I have to say
right now,
>> it might cause a war in the church."
>> That I don't know. Yeah,
>> if that's why she said but I'm telling
you
I'm telling you
no uh lawn this is this is after slavery
this is 1805 this is 1895 I'm sorry this
is 1895 this is 1900 1899 1905 1907
where she's making these statements
talking about the reviving of slavery
and the spirit of slavery not being
dead. And now
now here comes the conversation in 1907
with PT man
asking her questions regarding slavery.
Listen to this dialogue you guys. I
didn't even realize that we've been
offscreen for all this time.
>> It's okay. This is where they don't have
Okay. Now we're going back.
>> They're looking at Yeah. the more
important thing. Okay, PT man, I have
thought that the same things were true
about the blacks. You know, years ago,
you made the statement that the time
would come when there would be a
terrible race war in the South. I do not
know whether you ever said it in so many
words, but you intimated that slavery
would exist again.
Ellen White responds, "Just as soon as
people begin to make any kind of
movement to educate the blacks, there
are some who are determined that it
shall not be done." This is 1907, you
guys. This is after the civil war.
Pan,
it is the common talk all over the South
that there will be a race war within the
next few years. Senator Tilman has
talked in it in the House. Governor
Elect Hulksmith and Tilman have public
have published a plan that they are
advocating everywhere. Their plan is
something like this that they will
divide every county into districts and
every negro is to be counted is to be
numbered. He will have a brass plate
strapped to his arm with a leather strap
giving his number 536 or 602 6023 or
whatever it may be. And then he is never
to be allowed outside of that district
without a passport from the officers.
Ellen White, there will be slavery just
as verily as it has been only upon a
basis that is more favorable and secure
to the white people. This is 1907.
>> Listen to what PT began response.
more secure because they do not have to
feed the negroes and care for them. Then
if the negro has got outside that
district or if he is loafing and not
working, they can put him in the chain
gang for a year.
Ellen White,
that is the danger. That is why I have
pleaded and intreated intreated and
intreated for the work to be done in the
south because I knew that this very race
war would be introduced
>> slavery upon a more favorable
>> you kind of sped through that there was
a caution to the reader or I don't know
people find that interesting.
I'm not sure.
I thought I saw that.
>> No, no, no. Okay, that's the next slide.
I'll get to that in a second.
>> Okay. Sorry.
>> When Ella White talks about slavery on a
more favorable bas uh basis for the
white people. And PT man responds,
"Yeah, because they won't have to uh um
feed them or and house them."
>> And then he says, "They'll just put him
in prison.
>> Mercy. They'll just put them in prison.
>> Do you guys understand
>> what is being discussed in 1907
>> about the current times?
>> And then think about how who is put in
jail more often than anybody else and
how these are just stated as statistical
facts probably because black people
just, you know,
have in have uh inherent issues.
There's so much I want to say, but it's
not. Yeah, it would have it'll have us
here for a long time.
Um
there's so much to say but the um
like somebody said it in the chat which
is going I'm going I'm going I've always
thought similar to what they have stated
um that the new slavery is
our crim criminal justice system but to
get there
>> because remember before like um in the
in the 50s and prior like black people
were getting educated and getting
degrees and owners of banks and becoming
all these different you know
professional jobs and positions. But
then
in the early 60s, maybe late 50s, drugs
were pumped into the communities
>> and then black people were getting
longer sentences, right,
>> for the same crimes committed by their
white counterparts,
>> right?
>> So you guys, you got to understand like
this is not
>> that was a planned system that was
planned to try to break down.
In case you think this is a political
talk, blame Ellen White because I'm just
reading you what she said.
>> This is not me saying, "Hey, let me say
this." I'm just telling you what she
said.
>> And and what I want you to understand
that the spirit of the beast doesn't
change.
>> I want you to listen to this to this
statement. This is a rough statement,
you guys. This is rough, but I need to
read it. January 9, 1886, Adventist ruin
herald. It says this. Our readers are
perhaps very generally aware that the
constitution constitutional amendment in
regard to slavery has become a law and
as we published this week under the
heading slavery abolished in connection
with this piece read another head
another headed the shrew untamed
and see what the South Carolina
considers what South Carolina considers
the adoption of that amendment.
As for the people of the south of the of
the southern states, the hellish spirit
of slavery is part and parcel of their
being. This is an 18 in the 1860s,
y'all.
>> And the leopard will sooner change his
spots than they cease to cherish it in
their hearts.
>> A good brother recently said to us that
he used to think it was cruel in the
children of Israel to exterminate the
Canaanites as they did. But now, said
he, we have a practical illustration of
this point in the Southern Rebellion.
To get the spirit of slavery out of this
nation, it will be necessary to wipe out
of existence the former sla southern
slaveholders, men, women, and children.
It is born and bred in them, and will
die only when they die. He is right. It
may be asked if this action of the
government does not affect our view of
the two-horned beast. Not at all. We
believe that it is towards God's people,
the visible church, that the lamblike
pretense and the dragon voice of this
power is to be manifested. If we mistake
not, we shall soon see enough to
fulfill, which means to fill full this
specification. Now, let me say this. The
author here is not calling for the death
of of racist people. No,
>> he's simply saying it has been so inbred
in so many in the south
>> at that time that it is part of their
being.
>> It's been taught so deeply. It's been
ingrained so much. So beloved, when we
say that the beast does not change,
>> the beast doesn't reform, please
understand what we're saying. We're not
saying, you know, all people are racist.
I'm not saying all of particular people
are racist. We I am saying that there
are black people who are racist against
white people.
>> And I know there's a talk about well the
power, you know, black people can't be
racist towards white people. Listen,
>> you can hate a white person in your
heart.
>> Black people generally though do not
have the power to inflict the kind of
persecution that the white community
has.
>> Right? We don't have that kind of power
in society where we can say, you know
what, we're going to make y'all slaves
>> or you know what? We're gonna stop you
from getting, you know, uh, loans and
and and loans in these banks and lo
we're just going to
>> we're going to discriminate against you
here.
>> That's right. We don't have that that
that um political or financial power
>> to discriminate
>> against a white population. But ra you
can be hateful in your heart,
>> racist in your heart
>> towards white people, towards black
people, towards Chinese people, right?
Racism is not a one-way thing.
>> It's not. But the exercise of power
because of racism is often in this
nation, it is a one-way thing.
>> I I I'm not making that up. Okay. So,
so
let's talk about Jim Crow
because I want you to again notice
dragon talk. And you guys, if you could
give me a little bit more time, I think
I can wrap this up. And I know that my
wife has not even looked at the clock to
know that I have gone over time.
>> I have looked at the clock, but
>> it's important.
>> It's important. Let's talk about Jim
Crow.
>> You all better be there with me in
church. See, Living Mana online church
tomorrow. We start at 12:00 p.m. Central
time.
>> Okay.
>> If I'm going this late, you guys gota
Yeah. You guys got to be there.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, Brock, uh, you said, "I've
never met a black person that was racist
simply because someone was white."
Never. Meet the Hebrew Israelites.
>> Yeah. You just haven't You just haven't
met him yet.
>> The Hebrew Israelites literally believe
the the black Hebrew Israelite movement
literally believes that white people are
the devil.
>> Yeah. and cannot be saved and will be
slaves of the black people of black
people.
>> Yeah, we'll make them slaves.
>> Um when Jesus sets up his kingdom on the
earth, that is literally their belief.
>> That's pretty racist.
>> And it's a racist and satanic dragonlike
belief.
>> It's the same spirit.
>> Same spirit.
>> All right. Bob Jones
Bob Jones uh delivers a radio address in
1960 called Is Segregation Scriptural?
Is segregation scriptural? And I want
you to listen to the dragon speak.
Okay, so someone says Bob Jones is a
racist. How many of you would say Bob
Jones was racist?
>> Put a one in the chat if you would say
he was racist.
Two in the chat if you say he wasn't.
Yeah. Listen y'all,
>> the way that Hebrew Israelites talk to
white people, they talk to them like
they are literally dogs.
>> I mean, it's
>> it's horrible. Just go on YouTube. Just
look up some I mean it's like they'll
tell white people straight to their
face, "Yeah, you're lost. You will be
you will be our slaves."
>> I I mean it's
>> Yeah, it's crazy, y'all. It's crazy.
Okay. So,
so Bob Jones,
remember now what's happening is they're
about to integrate schools and Bob Jones
from Bob Jones University is is
vehemently against this
and
he's going to give this address and here
it is. Let's put it up on the screen.
Now, you might say Bob Jones is racist.
Back in the day, Bob Jones would have
challenged you on that. Founder of Bob
Jones University. Yep. Listen to this.
>> And it has a whole a huge homeschool
>> huge home school curriculum. Yep.
>> Huge. Huge. Huge.
>> Yeah.
>> So, here's what Bob Jones says in his
Easter radio address 1960. In recent
years, there has been a subtle satanic
effort to undermine people's faith in
the Bible. And the devil has helped the
race along until men have put their own
opinion above the word of God. You will
find that practically all the troubles
we are having today have come out of the
fact that men in many instances have
ceased to believe in an authoritative
Bible.
I'm skipping some paragraphs here so
just bear with me. For instance, we are
living in the midst of a race turmoil
all over the world today. Look at what
they are facing in Africa and look at
what we are facing in this country. It
is all contrary to scripture. It is all
contrary to the word of God. And I'm
going to show you how the Bible is
perfectly clear on races, just as clear
as it can be. If we would just listen to
the word of God and not try to overthrow
God's established order, we would not
have any trouble. God never meant for
America to be a melting pot to rub out
the line between the the nations. That
was not God's purpose for this nation.
When someone goes to the overthrowing of
When someone goes to overthrowing his
established order and goes around
preaching pious sermons about it, that
makes me sick. For a man to stand up and
preach pious pious sermons in this
country and talk about rubbing out the
line between the races, I say it makes
me sick. I have had the sweetest
fellowship with colored Christians, with
yellow Christians, with red Christians,
with all sorts of Christians. The
sweetest fellowship anybody has ever
had. We have had Christians have always
had it. We have never had any trouble
about that. God put the Africans over
there. They are fine people. They are
intelligent people. Do not think that
they're inferior in any way. That is not
so. But we should have sent missionaries
over there and Africa should have been a
great nation of colored Christians. If
we had done what God had told us to do
and sent the gospel to them and made a
Christian nation out of them instead of
bringing them over here and selling them
into slavery, Africa could have been a
great nation of colored Christians. What
we did was wrong and it was not right.
It cannot be justified. We should not
try to justify it. But racially, we have
separation in the Bible. Let's get that
clear. Now, you colored people, listen
to me. If you had not been brought over
here and if your grandparents in slavery
days had not heard that great preaching,
you might not even be a Christian. You
might be over there in the jungles of
Africa today unsaved.
>> But you are here in America where you
have your own schools and your own
churches and your own liberties and your
own rights with certain restrictions
that God Almighty put above you put
about you. Restrictions that are in line
with the word of God. The Jews had lived
as a separate race. They have been
separate for the for from the other
races of the world. They have been
miraculously preserved. Now they have a
homeland. They are back there today. And
what a wonderful thing is happening. The
time has come when good folks down here
in the south, the good colored people
and the good white people need to use
our heads. We should not let this
outside agitation disturb us down here.
There is no problem here. But it could
be a problem. It could be a problem in
California. It could be a problem
anywhere. Whenever you get a situation
that rubs out the lines that God has
drawn between races, whenever that hap
what whenever that happens, you're going
to have trouble. This is what is
happening today in this country. All
this agitation is a communistic
agitation to overthrow the established
order of God in this world.
>> Mercy.
>> The communist influence is at work all
about us. Certain people are disturbing
the situation. They talk about the fact
that we are going to have one world. We
will never really have one world until
this world heads up in God. We're not
going to have this one world by man
rubbing out the line that God has
established. He's marking the lines and
you cannot rub them out and get away
with it. Let me keep reading. I'm almost
done. Some of those some of them own
slaves and some of them did not. And
some of them were slaves and some of
them were not. Back in those days, they
believed the Bible. And God called this
nation into existence to be a witness to
the world and to be true to the word of
God. Do not let these religious liberals
blow their bubbles of nothing over your
head to get you upset and disturbed.
Let's get back to the word of God and be
sensible. And then he prays, "Our
heavenly father, bless our country. We
thank thee for our ancestors. We thank
thee for the good Christian people,
white and black. We thank thee for the
ties that have bound these Christians,
white people, and the Christian colored
people together through the years. And
we thank thee that white people who had
a little more money helped them build
their churches and stood by them. And
when they got sick, they helped them. No
nation has ever prospered or been
blessed like the colored people in the
south.
Help these colored people not get swept
away by all the propaganda that is being
put out now. Help us to see this thing
and to understand God's established
order and to be one in Christ and to
understand that God has fixed the
boundaries of the nation so we would not
have any trouble or misunderstanding.
Keep us by thy power and for thy glory
for Jesus name. Amen
and amen.
>> Somebody if I close my eyes and just let
you read,
>> does somebody want to say amen? I would
think you would have been reading
something somebody wrote today.
>> Today
the liberals,
the communists,
>> we did you a favor.
>> We did you a favor.
>> It was good that you came here.
>> Wait a minute. You're taking Bob Jones
out of context. He's not a racist. He
likes black people. What are you talking
about? He
Did you read the thing? Did you read the
whole thing?
The whole thing said that he likes black
people.
Where is he?
Dragon talk gets better and better
sounding lamblike. That's what changes.
It continues to sound more and more
lamblike, but it is still the same
spirit.
And when we cannot recognize that,
when we fail to recognize dragon talk,
what we're saying is that
we actually end up believing the lie of
the dragon talk and embracing that
ourselves so that we can no longer
recognize the dragon spirit And we
excuse the dragon spirit and we talk
about the context of the dragon spirit
and why you need to really hear what
what hear Bob Jones's heart. He's not
Listen, the guy sounds good. He prayed.
Did you get that? He prayed.
What are you talking about? This guy is
trying to help the black communities and
help the black people and and what are
you saying, man? Are you just trying to
cause trouble and strife?
You know, I had mentioned at the
beginning of the uh back to the basic
series that we did, but the I don't know
how many who are watching watched the
4hour
um started off as a Sabbath school, but
actually did the whole church with Kevin
Burton and Benjamin Baker. Mhm.
>> But it talked about
I mean the beginning of
Adventist being able to get swept up
into
um not understanding Revelation 13
properly
started in 1919
>> 1915 no 1919 I don't like
>> early 1900s
>> early 19 didn't want to be considered
communist
>> right
>> and so they began to change
>> that very thing, you guys.
>> Right.
>> No, no, no, no. The dragon, the beast
hasn't been speaking like a dragon.
That's in the future.
>> That's in the future.
>> That's when that started.
>> That's when it started. We didn't want
to be labeled as communists.
We were more concerned
>> mercy
>> about falling in line.
>> And we're seeing the fruit
>> the fruit of that now. Like it's deep.
>> This is okay. since we're all up late
together studying the Bible. Um,
this is splitting the church. I mean, if
you're wondering why we're up
while I'm allowing you to be up at 10:42
live is because this is this is really
important. This is splitting the church.
I don't know if you guys don't don't
isolate and stay in your little bubble
and just um
talk. I don't know how to say it, but
just you have to realize, come out of
your
>> bubble,
>> echo chamber and bubble and listen to
what other people are saying because you
will hear that this is splitting the
church.
>> It is.
>> Listen y'all, tomorrow my sermon is left
Jesus, right Jesus. There's two Jesuses
and I'm letting you know they are both
the wrong Jesus.
Sneak pre sneak preview for those of you
that stayed up late tonight. Sneak
preview for what's coming tomorrow. All
right, I got just a few more slides.
We're done. I promise you.
>> It is almost midnight on the east coast.
>> Okay, listen. We're almost there, you
guys.
>> We're almost there. You're going to get
these slides, but you got to see this.
Okay, here is the climax of this of this
message tonight. Revelation 16:3. I saw
three un unclean spirits like frogs come
out of the mouth of the dragon and out
of the mouth of the beast and out of the
mouth of the false prophet. H
>> maybe having to do something with
deception through speaking
>> speaking like a dragon. Listen,
when we when we deny the dragon voice,
when we spend
years
>> denying the voice of the dragon, when
the dragon voice speaks in our faces, we
can't hear it. We can't recognize it. He
could be telling you, "Hey guys, dragon
voice here."
And you'll be like, "What? I heard
glorious things. What do you mean?
>> Wow. Mercy.
>> Exhibit 8,
please listen to what was said
>> at a recent event by Steven Miller.
>> Who is okay?
>> You have to say who Steven Miller is
though.
>> A very high up person in the government.
>> He's
he's not the chief of staff, but he is
an adviser in the White House. Okay,
>> here we go.
So, I want you to notice
the us and the they in this speech.
Let's listen.
the storm and our enemies cannot
comprehend our strength, our
determination, our resolve, our passion.
Our lineage and our legacy
hails back to Athens, to Rome, to
Philadelphia, to Montichello. Our
ancestors built the cities. They
produced the art and architecture. They
built the industry.
Erica stands on the shoulders of
thousands of years of warriors of women
who raised up families, raised up city,
raised up industry,
raised up civilization,
who pulled us out of the caves and the
darkness into the light. The light will
defeat the dark. We will prevail over
the forces of wickedness and evil.
They cannot imagine what they have
awakened. They cannot conceive of the
army that they have arisen in all of us.
Because we stand for what is good, what
is virtuous, what is noble. And to those
trying to incite violence against us,
those trying to fment hatred against us,
what do you have?
You have nothing. You are nothing. You
are wickedness. You are jealousy. You
are envy. You are hatred. You are
nothing. You can build nothing. You can
produce nothing. You can create nothing.
We are the ones who build. We are the
ones who create. We are the ones who
lift up humanity.
You thought you could kill Charlie Kirk?
You have made him immortal.
[Music]
Yeah, I'm sorry guys. I don't know what
happened to that clip just now. And the
most important part where he says, "You
have awakened the dragon." I don't know
how that got cut out.
>> I don't know how that got cut out.
>> But you guys, I want you to hear.
>> He said that at the beginning.
>> He said it at the end. He said at the
end. Okay. Yeah.
>> The applause that was going on in an
audience full of Christians as he was
saying you are not now who the you was.
I still don't know. I mean I think I
know but it sound it sounded like a
personal threat. Like there's we and
there's you. And the we that build
things was not like us as Americans and
then you as like you know the Japanese
or the Russians. He was talking to
people in America. And I'm like, who are
the ones that build things? And then who
are the ones that are nothing, have
nothing,
>> are dirt,
>> you are nothing.
>> You are nothing. And Christians
applauding this.
And then prayer.
>> Prayer and weeping
and and moving emotional
Christian music.
I don't know how that got cut out.
>> I'm gonna try another one.
>> God saved our president, President
Trump, from an assassin's bullet for
this moment.
And what
does the Apostle Paul in Romans say
about a godly leadership?
He says that rulers
wield the sword
for the protection of good men
and for the terror of evil men.
May we pray that our rulers here,
rightfully instituted and given power by
our God, wield the sword for the terror
of evil men in our nation in Charlie's
memory.
Yeah, I'm going to pause it right here.
the desire to call the government to
wield the sword using scripture
and
presenting the enemy as all who oppose
Christianity
is an offthe-wall
insane
thing.
>> Many of us knew it was coming and never
thought it would happen. Maybe maybe we
didn't think it happened in our lifetime
or wouldn't happen so quickly. What?
This is happening on a world stage
where our government and I don't know if
you saw
>> but they had the secretary of state the
whole
>> the whole cabinet was there. They spoke
and they there was a a moment where they
said thank you all the cabinets are here
and God has given you the power of the
sword to execute judgment on the wicked.
And I was like,
are we in Germany? Like, what's going on
right now?
>> That's what I was going to say. It it
did when you hear the roar of the of the
audience. But this is the interesting
thing that
Satan thought he was clever. I guess I
don't know. But
what draws so many advocates
>> evil are terrified
>> to
>> and where the good and the faithful at
least the moral people of our nation can
live in peace that debate in peace
disagree in peace and start families in
peace it's it's horrible
>> and so we want to thank the
administration for being here and
carrying out that godly mission of
wielding the sword against evil
>> but then I thinking about the whole
5hour funeral. They praised him as a man
and his relationship with God, but they
never once mentioned that
>> against
>> he spent 24 hours
from Friday night sundown to Saturday
night sundown, not even looking at his
phone.
>> They never mentioned that.
We'll get to
>> I want to live in a country where the
evil are terrified and where the good
and the faithful and the moral people of
our nation can live in peace. You need
to understand that who you're about to
hear speaking Steven Wolf Christian
nationalists
>> you know runs in the same circles
and many of these others carrying out
that godly mission of wielding the sword
right after Charlie Kurt's assassination
and listen to the nonchalantness of what
they say
>> that the right will stay united for as
long as it takes uh and because we've
identified that enemy. We've identified
that enemy is the left and that the left
wants to destroy everything that's good,
true, and beautiful. It is a deranged
movement. It's, as people say, it's
filled with people who are disgusting
freaks who through their resentment want
to pretty much recreate their resentment
and their own self-hatred in the world.
they'll they'd rather live in filth um
and and see their enemies oppressed and
suppressed, that is the right, or
anything that is truly beautiful. This
is a moment where you can communicate to
your kind of normie evangelical friends
that the left actually is an evil
presence
>> and that we have through the the force
of law and through the constitution
these things can be suppressed. I mean
public public universities receive
public funding and so it should be
dictated what public it's not a private
university private universities unless
they take federal funding can do
whatever they want but if it's a public
university ought to support the the
virtues of the that the nation
recognizes virtues and not evil. Um so
there's things that by law you you ought
to suppress. The left dominates the
universities. They they not only do not
educate, they do not teach people um
what's good, true, and beautiful, they
actually inculcate the the sort of
thinking that would lead to the the the
at the very least the sort of people who
would support
the um the the murdering of of Charlie
Kirk. God is a God of justice and he's
ordained powers such that justice
would be exacted in would would be
enacted in in society and more than that
uh wickedness and unrighteousness would
be suppressed that the civil sword would
be a terror to wickedness. That's that's
why God ordained civil power. Um, and I
we have to kind of communicate that that
we can do that through our own heritage
and traditions and constitutional order
to suppress what is evil. That's the
whole purpose of government. That's the
purpose even of our government even
constitutionally. It is to suppress what
is evil um and to uh uh reward what is
good. And so I think there's a moment
where we can communicate that. And
that's not this is again it's like this
is not exploiting a moment. This is just
as you said it, people are jarred and
there's a call to conscience. There's
this where you're taken out sort of
transcending from the moment from your
media concerns and you begin to reflect
on what we've become, where we're at,
and what we need to do. And this is
where you can say, look, justice,
righteousness, we need to be a nation
under God. We need to return to what we
were at the founding and the century
really a century and a half throughout
this country which was to be a Christian
republic. Uh we need to return to that
and kind of like restore that the the
Christian politics that is to suppress
evil. So
>> um it's a moment that we have that that
uh we we can we can really um try to
communicate that the right will stay
united for.
>> Okay you guys.
>> So
we have just seen
something very very disturbing.
Dragon talk.
Dragon talk is a real thing.
And you can hear how nonchalantly like,
you know, hey, we're righteous. This is
good. The left, they're not even people.
They're a demonic force.
And I can tell you that there are it's
becoming more and more prevalent that
thought in our church
among people who share this.
The spirit of the dragon is entering
into the church. I mean that's what
Hitler used.
>> Absolutely. That's the only way he could
get
I mean as we shared in Sabbath school
last week even Adventists at that time
in Germany
>> Adventist in Germany
>> Adventists in the Rwanda
>> situation
>> politics had become so deep in them that
they began to see the other as purely
demonic
>> and in the name of righteousness you
probably should die because it's the
only way our nation will be saved. And
once you put nation above Jesus,
remember what they said, it is
expediented that one man perish that our
that our nation
>> not fall. Once you put nation above
Jesus,
which so many people are doing more and
more,
>> we're in a place where the warnings that
Ellen White was giving back there in
1907, and 1895,
um,
you cannot help but think, wow, is this
where we're are we really headed here?
And you and if you allow like the
political lines to be drawn so far that
you hate
the other side, that is the spirit
that's still the spirit of slavery.
>> Yeah.
>> Entering in. And we know that both sides
are going to come together. It's going
to it's not going to be
one political party
um against the Sabbathkeeping people and
you know joining the Sabbathkeeping
people. It's going to be those, you
know, the world is going to come
together to come against
>> Yep.
>> the Sabbath.
>> Once they get rid of their first enemy,
>> they will then turn their attention on
this enemy,
>> right?
>> The church.
>> Okay,
here's the last thing I need to share
with you guys. And these slides are
going to be rapid. Okay. So
when we cannot hear the voice of the
dragon, we will eventually join the
voice of the dragon.
Um here
here are various prophets
who are all over YouTube
saying that God has shown them the great
revival that is to come from
the unfortunate event that happened a
few weeks back.
If you remember my elephant in the room
series,
>> where I was talking about these exact
prophets,
prophets from the NRA,
>> um, who were who were prophesying about
this great, you know, uh, joining of
church and state and all of these
things. And now they're all prophesying
of what a what a tremendous
opening
window opportunity this is. I'm not
going to play all their videos. I'm just
showing you very well known uh Sid Roth,
some of these other guys that that we've
talked about before. All talking about
the great revival.
And I cannot I cannot help but think
that as I hear many Adventists
saying the same thing,
let me let me fix my screen here. Sorry.
As I hear many among us saying the same
thing that these prophets are saying,
um I'm not saying that it is that
necessarily makes it wrong. I'm just
saying it makes me a little bit nervous
>> that
many of us are saying the same thing
that these prophets are saying
>> in the Adventist minds that that are
saying some of these same things. They
think
>> this is well in their mind
the
the beast is not really
>> Yeah. Beast hasn't spoken yet,
>> right? And
>> so we can we can connect with these
movements because the beast hasn't
spoken yet,
>> but they're so attached and then they
think that when it does in their mind
speak that they're just going to be
like, "Oh yeah, okay. I can just I'm
just going to distance myself. I don't
but it's it's not going to be I it's not
>> but how do you break it off with a
friend that you you know how do you
break it off with someone you've been
friends with for so long you talk
together you laugh together you have
this you share the same hatreds oh man I
hate that too wow we really have a lot
in common
>> when what you have in common is what you
hate that's a dangerous thing you guys
hate or who you hate
That is not the basis of Christian
unity.
>> No,
>> that's a false unity.
>> And there's nothing wrong with preaching
Jesus and wanting to evangelize people.
It's it's mixing the government.
>> That's right.
>> And forcing
>> or trying to legislate
righteousness. That's always been I'm
sorry. As the fourth generation
Adventist that I am,
>> I didn't have to even study that for
myself.
>> It was just a known.
>> I heard that before I mean before I even
understood it from a preacher in a
pulpit coming from church. I heard that
from my grandfather. I heard that from
my grandmother. I heard that from my
mom. Like that was just
>> Yeah.
>> basic Adventism 101.
>> Yep. And it's not so basic
anymore.
So
that was my one hour presentation, one
hour prophetic time,
>> guys. I thought it would go two and it's
gone three.
>> Wow. I think this is our longest.
>> Uh, no.
>> No.
>> Outside of Kevin Burton's?
>> No. Well, no. Kevin Burton is tied with
um
oh my goodness I'm forgetting the name.
You always name things different. Um
Bible All Day.
>> Bible All Day.
>> Bible All Day and Kevin Burton is like
four hours.
>> Oh wow. Yeah.
>> Didn't know that. Okay. So this is not
that bad then.
>> But it wasn't on a um
Bible All Day wasn't on a um Friday
night,
>> right?
>> Where we have to get up and
>> Yeah.
>> like do a whole church service in the
morning.
>> Yeah.
>> Actually, praise God. We don't start I
shouldn't say praise God but our church
is not so early in the morning. So
>> I guess with that this is not so bad.
Actually we start at 12 pm central time
and I want to see all of you there.
Yeah.
>> That's why I wore this shirt
>> tomorrow morning. Left Jesus
right Jesus.
>> Yes. And with what you
>> you do not want to miss it.
>> You don't want to miss it.
>> Not want to miss it.
>> So honestly come and be blessed. It's uh
we have an amazing Sabbath school.
Again, we're talking about the Christian
Art of War, which is a book that Pastor
Meyers wrote, I think at least 17 years
ago. We have a Sabbath school panel. Two
of our amazing panelists are
17, 18 years old, amazing young people,
and others. So, come and be blessed.
You're going to learn some powerful
things on how to defeat your enemy,
which is Satan.
>> Which is Satan. And then you'll hear the
>> which is yourself. Which is yourself.
>> Self is the greatest enemy.
>> All right guys, well I'm glad you all
tuned in and um hopefully you guys this
study has been a blessing to you. Um
maybe hopefully it has it has opened
some eyes. Um, if I've said anything
that you want to take offensively,
please know that I um I do not mean it
to be offensive, but you know, speaking
the truth boldly seems to be a popular
thing, you know, that we that Adventists
like to say, speak the truth boldly. So,
I'm speaking the truth boldly. Whether
people like it or don't like it or want
to hear it or don't or don't want to
hear it, I'm speaking it hopefully not
in an offensive way, but trying to wake
us up so that we don't get caught up in
dragon speak,
>> right?
>> Okay.
>> Um, well, I don't want to answer the
Well, anyway,
>> I'm gonna say this. I know this. This
had to be good because Mondo is still up
and Mondo I know that you be in bed by
like X amount of time like this time in
your back. He was like that.
>> He wasn't like that back in the day, but
now he's like that.
>> Now, now he goes to bed early.
>> Um
>> I just want to say somebody said, "Hey
pastor, I know you have an online
church, but when do you fellowship with
people or whatever? You got to come
check Living Man Church out. We do more
fellowship
>> on." Believe it or not, don't just take
my word for it. Come and experience it
for yourself. We do we do we do a lot of
fellowship, a lot of connections.
>> Just come and see.
>> Yeah.
>> Come and see.
>> Amen.
>> All right. Good night, guys. Go to bed.
It's late. What are you doing up?
>> We still we still have to end in prayer.
But again, just a selfless plug. Living
man church. You can see it on Power of
the Lamb, but Living Mana Church has its
own YouTube channel, which is my Living
Mana. Starts at 12:00 PM Central time.
That's Sabbath school. Um, and it's
going to be amazing. And then church
service follows.
>> Amen.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Thank you everyone. Um,
sis, I see you.
I see you. I see the great guy's
message. Amen. Amen. Amen. All right.
>> Also, I'm I get to pray because you
talked for three hours. Is your voice
tired now?
>> Yeah.
>> It takes three hours to get it tired.
Okay, let's pray.
>> Heavenly Father, Lord, thank you uh for
this message, Lord, or this Bible study
together, Lord. And um Lord, I know so
many things were shared and I just pray
that everyone um will not just take this
um study that was done tonight, but that
they will go and study and pray through
this for themselves, Lord. Um, and we
just thank you for um, providing so much
information, Lord, in your word and
Lord, also um, through your prophet,
Ellen White, um, and just the things
that you showed her, which really shows
us, um, that she really was a prophet,
Lord. And so, um, again, we just thank
you for your Sabbath. Thank you for the
rest that it brings, Lord. And we're all
going to go get some rest at this time.
And so, Lord, again, just thank you for
this study in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
Amen. All right, y'all. God bless you
and um
>> happy Sabbath.
>> Happy Sabbath. Happy Sabbath.